<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>MountAye·Blog</title>
        <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en</link>
        <description>Intellectual thinking is a lifestyle.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 22:03:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <image>
            <title>MountAye·Blog</title>
            <url>https://blog.mountaye.com/assets/img/before_h2.png</url>
            <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>Rights Reserved 2024, MountAye</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.doc | OPT Workshop Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/OPT-workshop-notes</link>
            <guid>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/OPT-workshop-notes</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OPT is the abbreviation of Optional Practice Training.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="who-is-eligible">Who is eligible<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#who-is-eligible"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="pre-completion">Pre-completion<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#pre-completion"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Before graduation, need to talk with advisor, not common</p>
<h3 id="post-completion">Post-completion<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#post-completion"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>after graduation,</p>
<p>have entered the US, and have been in F1 status for 2 semesters</p>
<p>or graduates except for dissertation</p>
<ul>
<li>ABD: all but dissertation, finish before the end of EAD date</li>
<li>Otherwise need to go back home and complete the degree</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="opt-basics">OPT basics<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#opt-basics"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>related to your field of study</p>
<p>still an F1 student, not a work visa.</p>
<p>12 months OPT per level of education, not cumulative</p>
<p>eligible STEM degrees for extension of post-complete OPT, or pending H1B</p>
<p>no job offer is required to apply.</p>
<p>allows to change jobs and have multiple jobs</p>
<p>employer does not have to do anything, applicant is sponsoring themselves</p>
<p>can do paid/unpaid, this university cannot do unpaid work.</p>
<h2 id="only-work-after-authorization">Only work after authorization<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#only-work-after-authorization"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>not eligible to work until EAD card</p>
<p>no exception</p>
<p>need to create SEVP portal account after the OPT is approved and after the start date</p>
<p>need to report on change: US home address, employer and address, start and end date of employment</p>
<h2 id="do-not-accrue-more-than-90-days-of-unemployment">Do not accrue more than 90 days of unemployment<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#do-not-accrue-more-than-90-days-of-unemployment"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>within the authorization period on EAD card</p>
<blockquote>
<p>20 hours to be considered employed</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="keep-document-and-f1-records-updated">Keep document and F1 records updated<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#keep-document-and-f1-records-updated"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>request OPT-I20</p>
<h2 id="only-enroll-part-time-in-classes-unrelated-to-the-current-or-future-field-of-study">Only enroll part-time in classes unrelated to the current or future field of study<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#only-enroll-part-time-in-classes-unrelated-to-the-current-or-future-field-of-study"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>reach out to OISS advisor</p>
<h2 id="travel-outside-us">Travel outside US<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#travel-outside-us"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>possible with documents</p>
<ol>
<li>passport</li>
<li>F1 visa</li>
<li>I20 with signature</li>
<li>EAD</li>
<li>proof of employment (optional)</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>while OPT application pending is possible, but risky</strong> because the EAD will be mailed to your US address</p>
<h2 id="verify-admission-status-i94-record-is-correct">Verify admission status I94 record is correct<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#verify-admission-status-i94-record-is-correct"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p><a href="http://i94.cbp.dhs.gov" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">i94.cbp.dhs.gov</a></p>
<h2 id="summary">summary<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#summary"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-05-19-main-status.png" alt="how to maintain the OPT status"><figcaption>how to maintain the OPT status</figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="who-can-apply-for-extension">Who can apply for extension<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#who-can-apply-for-extension"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="24-month-stem-opt-extension">24-month STEM OPT extension<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#24-month-stem-opt-extension"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>aply during the last 90 days end of OPT</p>
<p>USCIS must receive before the end</p>
<p>must have a job</p>
<p>employer must enroll in E-verify</p>
<p>requires a plan (Form I-983)</p>
<h3 id="h1b-petition-pending-or-approved-may-requested-a-cap-gap">H1B petition pending or approved may requested a “cap gap”<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#h1b-petition-pending-or-approved-may-requested-a-cap-gap"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>cap gap employer file H1B application on April 1</p>
<p>if approved, H1B starts on October 1</p>
<p>if OPT expires before Oct 1, “cap gap” extension is added in SEVIS until decision of H1B is decided</p>
<h2 id="application-process">application process<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#application-process"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<ul>
<li>workshop, get a packet</li>
<li>request OPT I20  form from OISS advisor</li>
<li>prepare and submit form I-765 OPT application to USCIS</li>
<li><strong>must be in US to apply for OPT</strong></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="application-timeline">application timeline<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#application-timeline"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p><strong>application estimated to take 4 weeks.</strong></p>
<p>90 days before program end date → I-20 end date → 60 days after program end date</p>
<p>pick requested start date: 1 day after I 20 end date → end of 60 day grace period</p>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-05-19-time-window.png" alt="time window of OPT application"><figcaption>time window of OPT application</figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="packet">Packet<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#packet"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="request-opt-i20">request OPT-I20<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#request-opt-i20"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>requested OPT start date form</p>
<p>academic advisor verification form <code>OR</code> ABD OPT form, one or the other</p>
<h3 id="the-packet-is-for-getting-opt-i-20-recommendation-from-oiss">The packet is for getting OPT I-20 recommendation from OISS<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#the-packet-is-for-getting-opt-i-20-recommendation-from-oiss"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h2 id="opt-i-20">OPT I-20<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#opt-i-20"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>application to USCIS with the recommendation from OISS</p>
<h3 id="evidence-files-to-upload-i-765--with-opt-i-20">evidence files to upload I-765  with OPT I-20<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#evidence-files-to-upload-i-765--with-opt-i-20"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>immigration docu: passport, I-94</p>
<p>previous OPT and CPT, can skip if you don’t have it</p>
<p>2 by 2 inches passport style photo; taken within 30 days; Public library, Walgreens, and CVS offer the service</p>
<h3 id="what-if-the-ead-start-date-is-after-the-end-date-of-the-grace-period">What if the EAD start date is after the end date of the grace period?<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#what-if-the-ead-start-date-is-after-the-end-date-of-the-grace-period"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>didn't quite hear the answer</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.doc | Job Search Efforts During March Meeting]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/job-search-efforts-during-march-meeting</link>
            <guid>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/job-search-efforts-during-march-meeting</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[[Translated by ChatGPT] 2 interviews and 1 focus session during March Meeting 2023.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="before-the-meeting">Before the Meeting<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#before-the-meeting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>The March meeting will be held in Las Vegas this year.</p>
<p>It's about two weeks away from the conference, and I developed folliculitis at the base of my chin where I have a beard. It quickly worsened into herpes zoster, commonly known as "internal heat" in Chinese medicine. The second semester of the American academic year ends in May, and I haven't made much progress on my thesis. I can't find a job, and the application season for postdoctoral programs is in full swing with paper submissions. I watched helplessly as the application deadlines for two projects passed by. The postdoctoral project shared by a neighboring research group reposted their job advertisement online shortly after I submitted my application materials. I also applied to two research institutes in Germany, with one already sending a rejection letter and the other not responding at all. In addition to all this, I need to prepare for my presentation at the conference. It's no wonder I'm feeling stressed.</p>
<p>On Friday, we had a rehearsal for the group's presentations. I had initially planned to reuse the slides from last year's conference but realized that the main content from my paper was missing. It made me realize that I had indeed accomplished quite a bit over the past year. After receiving the rejection letter from the German research institute, I felt down for a day. However, the trend of using ChatGPT quickly gained popularity. So I compiled a list of professors I had heard of during my doctoral studies and fed their research group homepage descriptions, along with an abstract of my paper generated by AI, to ChatGPT, asking it to compose an email. The result was decent, and I received a reply inviting me to meet during the conference. The person who responded is a well-known researcher who studies animal behavior using a cross-scale approach and manages two research groups in Europe and East Asia. They made a big impression at last year's conference and later came to give a lecture at my university. We had lunch together. Shortly before the meeting, someone on the APS (American Physical Society) mailing list sent a mass email advertising a job opportunity. It turns out they are the current postdoc who will soon start a faculty position at a university in the western United States. Interestingly, they are currently working at the German research institute that rejected me. I can't help but feel a mix of envy and satisfaction knowing that they also fell for the ChatGPT-generated email trick.</p>
<h3 id="meeting">Meeting<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#meeting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>I walked to the conference venue and checked in. I received a name tag, which was just a thick piece of paper hanging from a string, without even a plastic cover.</p>
<p>After checking in, I surveyed the layout of the conference venue. The rooms related to biophysics were located on both sides of the first intersection in the main corridor. Each doorway had display boards indicating the themes of the speeches for each time slot. Unlike last year when I was the only one from our team attending, this year all three members of our team have presentations. In addition, Katie, a former master's student in our group, and her current classmates also have presentations. When I marked the schedule, I found that most of the interesting sessions conflicted with each other. Although I have social anxiety, I still feel that interpersonal relationships are important. Or perhaps it's because of my social anxiety that I feel interpersonal relationships are more important?</p>
<p>Back at the hotel, I received a reply from my group email to confirm a time one or two weeks after the March meeting for a remote interview. The purpose is for me to introduce my current work and explain how I can contribute to his laboratory. It's a bit unexpected because his group email mentioned that he would attend the conference, and my email also stated that I was willing to meet during the conference. Does this reply imply a lack of interest? I feel a little disappointed.</p>
<h3 id="interview-1">Interview 1<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interview-1"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>When I was wandering between different sub-venues and arrived late to one where the seats were already filled, I had to stand at the back. While I was standing and listening in one of the venues, a guy wearing a green jacket and carrying a sports backpack walked in. He listened for a while and then left. He seemed somewhat familiar, resembling the photos on ChatGPT's personal website.</p>
<p>Curious, I discreetly left the venue and saw him talking to a friend in the corridor, with the name tag on the front of his chest turned over. I temporarily left and explored around, discovering that coffee was available in the main corridor. I lined up and got a cup, then came back to investigate and confirmed it was him.</p>
<p>I greeted him, and it turned out that ChatGPT had been too verbose in his email and only mentioned that he was also attending the conference in March at the very end. I asked him when my presentation was scheduled and if he planned to attend, so we wouldn't need a Zoom meeting.</p>
<p>The title of my presentation during that time slot was quite peculiar, and it didn't seem to have much relevance to what I was working on. When I entered the waiting area, I noticed that apart from the two of us from our lab, all the other presentations in that session were focused on the same pattern and structure of a particular model organism. Our presentation came at the very end of the session, and I felt we performed well. When I started addressing the topic, I made a joke using the session's title, and we finished right on time. ChatGPT arrived at the venue about half an hour before my presentation, and after we finished, he left without coming up to talk to me.</p>
<p>Afterward, back at the hotel, I received an email from him, inviting me to meet the next afternoon. I searched his schedule on the conference website and found that it was right after his presentation. Looking at the title of his talk, it seemed to be about his recent paper. I fed the article into an AI tool to generate an abstract but didn't get a chance to read it before my classmates pulled me away to play...</p>
<p>His presentation was scheduled for the next afternoon and fell in the middle of the overall time slot. I entered the venue at the beginning of the session, and he arrived a little later, sat for a while, and then left. The venue was twice as large as when I gave my presentation, but it wasn't completely filled. While he was speaking, I was reviewing the article summary generated by AI from yesterday, feeling that it contained more information than most of the presentations I had heard up until that point. His presentation skills were also far above the average level. His research targeted a biological system one level higher than my current research focus, but the approach and process seemed similar. His research was much more advanced, both in theory and experimentation. Although the theory seemed to be a fairly traditional model in the field, it was still much better than just presenting experimental data like we did.</p>
<p>After the conference, we met in the corridor and found two seats. I showed him my slides, and he went through all the details, confirming that I would be working on gene editing in our lab's model organism. He also asked about the proportion of my work within the entire project.</p>
<p>Then, he asked a question that felt as significant as being confessed to in a romantic relationship: "What is the central question guiding your research career?" Ah, my brain immediately crashed. Seeing me struggling, the guy said I could speak in Chinese, as he understood it but couldn't speak it. Finally, when I felt cornered, I told the truth - I just wanted to coast through academia, eat and wait for death. If</p>
<p>ChatGPT has arrived, and we have super-intelligent AI, who needs physics anymore? Physics doesn't exist anymore. The guy chuckled at my response.</p>
<p>He then asked me to ask questions. I inquired about the duration of holidays, and he replied that it followed the school's policy. Those who have cultured cells should know that they might have to go to the school on weekends, so as long as the workload is sufficient, there are no attendance requirements on weekdays.</p>
<p>Overall, the conversation went quite smoothly. In the end, he mentioned that he would send me an email and asked for two or three ways to contact me, as well as a recommendation letter.</p>
<h3 id="interview-2">Interview 2<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#interview-2"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Originally, I had a good impression of this esteemed person, but since it was the first day of the conference, I thought maybe everyone hadn't settled in yet. Therefore, I sent an email on Tuesday to confirm the meeting time, and as a result, we arranged to meet on Friday at noon, next to the DBIO service desk.</p>
<p>I had planned to prepare in advance, as his research group had three or four presentations, but most of them clashed with my own presentation or the previous interview. In the end, I only attended one of them.</p>
<p>Friday at noon turned out to be the last session of the entire conference. The DBIO table had already been removed, and everyone seemed eager to leave. After about ten minutes past 12 o'clock, I finally met the person, and five minutes later, the person I was talking to left. Everyone was busy packing up and closing the doors. We found an empty room with a table and chairs that had already been moved out. Inside the room, there was only one student lying on the floor sleeping. The two of us sat down facing each other on the floor.</p>
<p>Just as I was about to take out my computer to go over my presentation, he waved his hand and asked me to briefly summarize my work orally. The subsequent series of questions and answers followed the same style, with the two of us sitting on the floor, exchanging rapid-fire questions and quick responses, resembling the agility of Zen. He started by asking why I chose to pursue my current work. I thought I gave a decent answer, but as I spoke, I realized that it was the answer from the previous interview. Why didn't I think of that earlier? Feeling a bit too pleased with myself, I forgot that this esteemed person was focused on studying behavior, not organizational structure. It could have been easily smoothed over, but I didn't handle it well. Then he asked about my favorite course during my undergraduate studies, a question he mentioned during our lunch break, so I pretended to be impressive. After that, he asked two significant questions: "How did a stinky experimenter like you end up begging for food in our theoretical group?" and "How did a stinky structuralist like you end up begging for food in our behavioral research field?" I didn't answer them well. Earlier, in my self-satisfaction, I mentioned having another job offer, which led to both sides being somewhat perfunctory during the latter part of the conversation.</p>
<p>Finally, he briefed me that the research in East Asia has sufficient funding, although he spends a considerable amount of time there every year, it's not always possible to meet in person for guidance. Regarding Europe, if I decide to join, he would need to specifically apply for funding. The meaning behind this was quite clear, so we politely agreed to take some time to consider it and said we could stay in touch via email in the future.</p>
<h3 id="symposium">Symposium<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#symposium"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>The symposium actually took place on the afternoon of the same day as my speech, right before the two interviews.</p>
<p>The so-called symposium was organized by several research institutions in Germany and aimed to promote information related to research conducted in Germany. It was quite far from the venues of the biophysics sessions. After my friend Katie finished her speech, I slipped out of the venue and rushed over. By the time I arrived, it had already begun. There were bagels, jam, and cheese on both sides of the entrance, and it was the first time in many days that I had lunch.</p>
<p>There were six or seven round tables in the venue, each with a small label indicating the name of a research institution. There were one or two staff members from each corresponding institute sitting at the tables. The host introduced each research institution in turn and gave the leaders of the institutions three to five minutes to introduce themselves. After that, it was free time. I noticed that the Max Planck Institute's table was near the bread, and since the other institutions didn't seem to focus much on basic scientific research, I found a chair and sat down. The head of the Max Planck Institute was an elder with white hair. His attire was more formal compared to the other participants, and he had a strong presence, resembling a wise figure.</p>
<p>The first question was about the difficulty of immigrating to Germany and whether Germany was somewhat exclusive. The elder replied that Germany is currently one of the most open countries in terms of immigration policies. Considering the phrase "one of the," and also taking into account that foreign graduates in non-academic positions in the beacon country have to draw lots to obtain a work visa, excluding the "borderline," this answer could not be considered wrong. Deutsche Welle had previously released a video with a similar statement, but that video had a follow-up phrase of "aber..." (but...).</p>
<p>Someone then asked about the projects and job structure at the Max Planck Institute. The answer was similar to what I had previously understood. Each research institution has the authority to recruit its own researchers. The duration of a postdoctoral position is generally two years, with extensions to three years or longer only when necessary. At the Max Planck Institute, except for the director, there are hardly any permanent positions for research positions. The institute serves as a stepping stone for researchers before they secure a permanent faculty position. However, whether it was a government regulation or something else, there was a rule stating that nine years after obtaining a doctoral degree, the employing institution must provide a permanent position. As a result, individuals are often dismissed before the end of those nine years. It wasn't asked whether this contradicted the previous answer.</p>
<p>When asked what kind of research the Max Planck Institute favors, the elder explicitly stated that they prefer more challenging and ambitious topics rather than safe topics pursued solely to obtain a faculty position. He even specifically mentioned the aim to explore topics and scholars that have the potential to receive Nobel Prizes in the future. This naturally differs from the American-style notion of verbal freedom and the actual practice of focusing on safe bets. It's interesting how the understanding of pragmatism can differ so greatly between two cultures—one rooted in long-term plans and top-down designs, and the other more focused on short-term gains.</p>
<p>Someone also asked about the criteria for selecting applicants at the Max Planck Institute. The answer was that each research institution has its own criteria. However, he also mentioned his own criteria: academic performance is the main factor, and when conducting research, one should have a clear understanding of the underlying physics. So, how is academic performance judged? It mainly depends on attending prestigious schools, followed by academic rankings. If the school's name is less well-known, higher academic rankings are expected. The answer was sincere, and it didn't evoke any sense of objection towards such obvious discrimination based on one's undergraduate alma mater, nor did it provoke any intention to challenge it.</p>
<p>This response is clearly targeting the American model, which emphasizes research experience and places greater importance on the authorship of papers. The backbone of a research group consists of Ph.D. students who do not need to spend time attending classes. How much contribution can undergraduate students applying for a Ph.D. make to the entire project? Moreover, these contributions are largely made by sacrificing their efforts in coursework. The sentence highlighted above is a sarcastic comment on this matter. Furthermore, considering the notorious reputation of the academic environment in China, overseas research experience is typically required. Apart from special programs like the Everest Plan that provide scholarships, most students have to self-fund and contact foreign mentors. This not only turns academic selection into a disparity unrelated to academia, linked instead to students' economic conditions, but also fosters an intermediary industry that sells such information. What academic justice is there in this policy?</p>
<p>However, let's consider how much academic performance can be reflected in a transcript. How many students openly ask their professors for grades when they intend to study abroad? Until a few years ago, there were even legitimate operations like "passing and retaking" courses at certain universities to alter transcripts. Not to mention the highly similar nature of examination questions across different subjects in China, which is detrimental to stability and unity. If attending prestigious schools is a requirement, then going abroad after high school graduation has far more advantages than going after undergraduate studies. It becomes a class-based filtering process, leading to the same destination through different paths.</p>
<p>Both of these scenarios involve individuals, each operating under a different moral framework, which is gradually deconstructed and distorted when translated into executable actions. Throughout this process, their own judgment is constantly outsourced. Outsourcing itself is not a problem, as division of labor is both a reflection of societal development and an important driving force. However, let's take an airplane as an example. Safely delivering passengers to their destinations requires coordination and trust between the crew and ground staff, but the safe arrival ultimately has objective standards. In the education and research system, the outcomes of its own cultivation are digested by itself. The selection process inherently involves the phenomenon of athletes acting as both players and referees. Some of the selected individuals may not be competent, while some of the non-selected ones may be capable. In that case, it would be straightforward: allocate all resources to the winners and cut off the paths for the losers...</p>
<p>Both models, in their mediocrity, peck at each other, and neither can replace the other. Ultimately, today's physics itself is lackluster. Leaving aside the magnificent breakthroughs during the birth of quantum mechanics and relativity, even the process of constructing the standard model was full of ad hoc solutions. Today, it is difficult to hope for its complete reversal. How much of the knowledge you solidly understand can be applied in your actual research? How many valuable works have you produced over these years of early involvement in research? Young people consider matters they believe are crucial to their future and destiny, but it is nothing more than a few bytes in their boss's email inbox. Whether they accept you or someone else, the difference is insignificant.</p>
<p>In short, there are no heroes in our time, which allows mediocre individuals to gain fame.</p>
<p>In the afternoon, a lady who had a conversation with "群发哥" (a nickname) the day before gave a speech shortly after him. Looking at her organization on the first page of the presentation slides, it seemed that she was a junior colleague in his doctoral laboratory and was about to join his current research institute. <del>In other words, she is the enemy who took away my offer</del>. So, I posted a complaint in my friend circle. Her speech exceeded the allotted time and was interrupted by the host. I was about to</p>
<p>add a comment saying "Exceeded the time, so bad," but considering that I had been posting quite a lot on my friend circle in the past few days, I refrained.</p>
<p>The only person I admired during my four years in university, "峰神" (a nickname), replied below, saying he had also considered applying to the same research institute. I asked him where he is now, and a few minutes later, I saw his reply: "Already started working." I quickly teased him, saying "Rich brother, lend me 50 yuan." However, the words spoken at the meeting reverberated in my mind, sighing and turning into a deep breath. I silently put away my phone.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.tex | Notes during APS March Meeting 2022 in Chicago]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/notes-during-APS-march-meeting-2022-Chicago</link>
            <guid>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/notes-during-APS-march-meeting-2022-Chicago</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes during the March Meeting in 2022 Chicago]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="physical-of-artificial-system">Physical of Artificial System<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#physical-of-artificial-system"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>some physical learning that does not have to be in equilibrium</p>
<h2 id="cell-fate">Cell fate<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cell-fate"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="xinhua-xings-talk">Xinhua Xing’s talk<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#xinhua-xings-talk"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>intro to differential geometry: Kamien, Rev Mod Phys 74:953 (2002)</p>
<p>WeiKang Wang, in silico vector field analysis</p>
<p>Waddington landscape 1957</p>
<p>Joanathan Weissman Lab (WI, MIT)</p>
<h3 id="marias-talk">Maria’s Talk<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#marias-talk"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Boston U, Pankaj Mahta Group.</p>
<p>extension  of work from Lang et al PLoS comput bio (2014)</p>
<p>found an order parameter, better than UMAP</p>
<h3 id="shubham-tripathis-talk">Shubham Tripathi’s talk<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#shubham-tripathis-talk"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>miimally frustrated topology</p>
<h3 id="glassy-fluctuation-">Glassy fluctuation ...<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#glassy-fluctuation-"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>proten and mRNA noise levels are Boltzmann distributed.</p>
<p>spin glass: frustration</p>
<p>free energy</p>
<p>gene expression noise can store information</p>
<h3 id="kraemer">Kraemer<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#kraemer"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>cell types in multicellular organisms</p>
<p>master regulator as order parameter</p>
<p><strong>Hopfield model</strong></p>
<p>forward and backward conditional probabilities</p>
<h3 id="logan-carpenter">Logan Carpenter<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#logan-carpenter"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>tissue homeostasis: birth and death</p>
<p>cellular Potts model</p>
<p>there is Hamiltonian!</p>
<p>CompuCell3D software</p>
<p>cell size distribution plot is very good</p>
<h3 id="los-talk">Lo’s talk<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#los-talk"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>UWashington</p>
<p>collision during cell cycle, replication and transcription</p>
<p>F-mean</p>
<h3 id="lambertio">Lambert.io<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#lambertio"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>bacterial persistence</p>
<p>CRISPER-dCas12a interference</p>
<p>massive parallel assay</p>
<h3 id="arkansas-u-talk">Arkansas U talk<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#arkansas-u-talk"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Reversibiliy and cell division dynamics of elongated Escherichia coli cells obtained at high pressure</p>
<p>a new cell division model</p>
<p>GCDM</p>
<p>continuous time Markov chain model?</p>
<h3 id="vivek">Vivek<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#vivek"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>microbial colonizing and phenotypes</p>
<p>Danio rerio</p>
<p>virio Z20</p>
<h3 id="louis-cortes">Louis Cortes<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#louis-cortes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>IPTG indeces lac operon</p>
<p>$f(t)=1-e^{-\frac{ln(2)}{t_{1/2}}(t-t_0)}$</p>
<h3 id="jintao-li">Jintao Li<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#jintao-li"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>cell competition</p>
<p>homeostasis pressure</p>
<h2 id="author--reference-session">Author &#x26; Reference Session<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#author--reference-session"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="criteria">criteria<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#criteria"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<ul>
<li>significantly advance physics</li>
<li>scientifically</li>
<li>letter
<ul>
<li>advance in field</li>
<li>open a new</li>
<li>solve a problem</li>
<li>be of great interest</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="for-authors">for authors<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#for-authors"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<ul>
<li>identify audience</li>
<li>take-home message</li>
<li>adequate literature</li>
<li>authorship &#x26; acknowledgment</li>
<li>additional info
<ul>
<li>suggested reviewer</li>
<li>conflicts of interest</li>
<li>related paper</li>
<li>PRL/X: justification for suitability exclusively to</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="referee">referee<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#referee"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<ul>
<li>novel, interesting, original</li>
<li>valid and reproducible</li>
<li>well presented</li>
<li>report
<ul>
<li>summary</li>
<li>technical details</li>
<li>decision explained</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>report requirements
<ul>
<li>substantiated</li>
<li>a reasonable level of details</li>
<li>no personal/self-serving remarks</li>
<li>timeliness</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="joint-submissions">joint submissions<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#joint-submissions"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h3 id="updated-physh">updated PhySH<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#updated-physh"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h2 id="k42-network-theory-and-applications-to-complex-systems">K42: Network Theory and Applications to Complex Systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#k42-network-theory-and-applications-to-complex-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="complex-contagion-unfolding-and-control">Complex Contagion: Unfolding and Control<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#complex-contagion-unfolding-and-control"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Adilson E. Motter, Northwest University</p>
<p>contagion</p>
<p>whack-a-mole effect</p>
<h3 id="physics-of-financial-networks">Physics of financial networks<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#physics-of-financial-networks"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>mono-layer networks: a network of ownership, a network of credit contracts between financial institutes</p>
<p>multi-layer  networks:</p>
<h2 id="non-equilibrium-i">Non-equilibrium I<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#non-equilibrium-i"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="success-landscape">success landscape<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#success-landscape"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h3 id="speed-fluctuation-of-bacterial-replisomes">speed fluctuation of bacterial replisomes<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#speed-fluctuation-of-bacterial-replisomes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h3 id="circadian-clocks-in-natural-environments">circadian clocks in natural environments<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#circadian-clocks-in-natural-environments"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>$\dot r = \alpha r(1-\frac{r^2}{R^2})$</p>
<p>$\dot \theta = \omega$</p>
<p>“decoder”</p>
<p>Leypunskiy 2017, Pittayakanchit 2018</p>
<h2 id="physics-of-social-interactions-i">Physics of social interactions I<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#physics-of-social-interactions-i"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="collective-sensing-in-slime-mold">collective sensing in slime mold<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#collective-sensing-in-slime-mold"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>slime molds sense concentrations of fructose in environments</p>
<p>hypotheses:</p>
<ul>
<li>evenly distributed across the network. density be the only parameter</li>
<li>at the growing tips</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="competition-for-fluctuating-resources-reproduces-statistics-of-species-abundance-over-time-across-wide-ranging-microbiotas"><a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/M03/2" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Competition for fluctuating resources reproduces statistics of species abundance over time across wide-ranging microbiotas</a><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#competition-for-fluctuating-resources-reproduces-statistics-of-species-abundance-over-time-across-wide-ranging-microbiotas"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>consumer-resource model: species abundance is solely dependent on resource functuations</p>
<p>Taylor’s law: distribution of abundance change is fit by a power law.</p>
<p>“their model” coarse grained consumer-resource. can predict many kinds of , different resource competition regimes.</p>
<h3 id="dog-congnition">Dog Congnition<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#dog-congnition"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Alexandra Horowitz.</p>
<p>Social play</p>
<h2 id="predicting-nonlinear-and-complex-systems-with-machine-learning-i">Predicting Nonlinear and Complex Systems with Machine Learning I<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#predicting-nonlinear-and-complex-systems-with-machine-learning-i"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="building-deep-learning-architectures-for-physics-chemistry-and-biology-with-geometric-algebra">Building Deep Learning Architectures for Physics, Chemistry, and Biology with Geometric Algebra<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#building-deep-learning-architectures-for-physics-chemistry-and-biology-with-geometric-algebra"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>finished soon after I arrived</p>
<p>vector institute</p>
<h3 id="quantum-thermal-machine-with-ml">Quantum thermal machine with ML<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quantum-thermal-machine-with-ml"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>BraXXXX, VQE</p>
<p>Finite time thermodynamics: compete between efficiency and power</p>
<p>energy change between two harmonic oscillators</p>
<p>differential programming, RL-like scheme</p>
<p>missed the flawed thermodynamic definition</p>
<h3 id="clarkson-university-reservoir-computing">Clarkson University: reservoir computing<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#clarkson-university-reservoir-computing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>reservoir computer: a kind of neural network, for forecasting dynamical systems but most of the parameters are chosen randomly. cheap but works well.</p>
<p>ESN Jaeger 2001</p>
<p>classic representation theorem by WOLD theorem</p>
<p>works because time soaks randomness. equivalent to logical NVAR (non-linear vector autoregression)</p>
<p>enjoys universal approximation theorem, even linear with non-linear readout.</p>
<p>VAR: vector autoregression</p>
<p>VMA: vector moving average</p>
<p>DMD</p>
<p>macket-glass equation as its example</p>
<h3 id="kims-recurrent-neural-programming-language">Kim’s recurrent neural programming language<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#kims-recurrent-neural-programming-language"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>also reservoir computer.</p>
<p>silicon computers represent with binary and compute sequentially.</p>
<p>neural computers use continuous symbols and compute distributedly</p>
<p>dRAM: dynamical random access memory</p>
<p>store a reservoir into another reservoir</p>
<p>another hot topic is Koopman's theory</p>
<h3 id="learn-complex-fluids-with-rheo">Learn complex fluids with rheo<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#learn-complex-fluids-with-rheo"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>RhINNs (PhysicsINNs): inform the NN with underlying physics/rheology</p>
<p>his model is called RhIGNet, and an improved “multi-fidelity RHIGNets”</p>
<h3 id="data-driven-selection-of-rheology-informed-nn">Data-driven selection of rheology-informed NN<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#data-driven-selection-of-rheology-informed-nn"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>same group as previous one.</p>
<p>model works better as it goes more complex, while data wants model to be simpler.</p>
<p>we should prioritize data range over size</p>
<h3 id="ml-for-robot-locomotion-in-flowable-materials">ML for Robot Locomotion in Flowable Materials<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#ml-for-robot-locomotion-in-flowable-materials"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>robot cars (RRP) climbing sand slopes</p>
<h3 id="predicting-clogging">Predicting Clogging<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#predicting-clogging"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>hopper flow</p>
<h3 id="analogical-reasoning-to-build-transferable-models">Analogical Reasoning to build Transferable Models<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#analogical-reasoning-to-build-transferable-models"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>model manifold: for a given data sampling method, points in parameter space can be mapped to a sampling space</p>
<p>manifold boundary approximation method</p>
<p>supremum principle</p>
<p>Wnt signalling network</p>
<h3 id="evidence-for-griffiths-phase-criticality-in-residual-neural-networks"><a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/M09/12" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Evidence for Griffiths Phase Criticality in Residual Neural Networks</a><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#evidence-for-griffiths-phase-criticality-in-residual-neural-networks"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>residual networks’ has Griffith phase, due to the design (sth.  and renormalization)</p>
<h2 id="n08-systems-far-from-equilibrium">N08: Systems Far from Equilibrium<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#n08-systems-far-from-equilibrium"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="hopping-particles">Hopping Particles<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#hopping-particles"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>math heavy</p>
<p>Doi representation, Jarzynski relation, Doi-Peliti field theory</p>
<p>generalized fluctuation-dissipition into non-equilibrium</p>
<p>no coarse graining or slow modes</p>
<h3 id="a-topological-fluctuation-theorem"><a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/N08/2" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">A topological fluctuation theorem</a><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#a-topological-fluctuation-theorem"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>$\Delta S_M = \frac{Q}{k_B T}n = \gamma n$</p>
<p>also math heavy</p>
<p>detailed TFT: symmetry of particle in vortex field is protected by topology</p>
<h3 id="tur-in-langevan-processes">TUR in Langevan processes<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#tur-in-langevan-processes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>TUR: thermodynamic uncertainty relation</p>
<p>$\frac{var(j)}j{}\ge \frac{2}{&#x3C;\Sigma>}$</p>
<p>probability distribution → rate function. don’t know how</p>
<p>“caveat” seems an abused word, another is “ansatz”</p>
<h3 id="reversal-symmetry-for-cyclic-paths-from-notre-dame">reversal symmetry for cyclic paths from Notre Dame<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#reversal-symmetry-for-cyclic-paths-from-notre-dame"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>detailed balance implies a reversal symmetry</p>
<p>expressed as Markov process: $\frac{p_i}{p_j} = \frac{l(i,j)}{l(j,i)}$</p>
<p>his work is just cycles in non-equilibrium systems</p>
<p>fluctuation theorem for <strong>cycle counts</strong>. PRE 2021</p>
<h3 id="emergence-and-breaking-of-duality-symmetry-in-generalized-thermodynamic-relations-from-unc-chapel-hill">emergence and breaking of duality symmetry in generalized thermodynamic relations from UNC chapel hill<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#emergence-and-breaking-of-duality-symmetry-in-generalized-thermodynamic-relations-from-unc-chapel-hill"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>foundation of thermodynamics, statistical mechanics, can be further founded upon classical or quantum mechanics</p>
<p>three times of Legendre transforms of internal energy ought to give 0, which breaks the reversibility of Legendre transform.</p>
<p>T. Hill 1963: added some sub linear term</p>
<p>they used mean of finite measurements</p>
<p>their understanding of thermodynamics is “nothing more than theories of probability”</p>
<h3 id="scaling-of-entropy-under-coarse-graining">Scaling of entropy under coarse graining<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#scaling-of-entropy-under-coarse-graining"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>entropy production rate</p>
<p>in 1 dimension Derrida)</p>
<p>dimension matters and data reduction may have non-trivial effects.</p>
<h3 id="kibble-zurek-effect-quench">Kibble-Zurek effect, quench<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#kibble-zurek-effect-quench"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>phase transitions</p>
<h3 id="discrete-non-linear-schroedinger-equation-by-federico">Discrete Non-Linear Schroedinger Equation by Federico<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#discrete-non-linear-schroedinger-equation-by-federico"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>phase transition again</p>
<h3 id="anormalous-thermal-relaxation-in-unimolecular-chemical-reactions">anormalous thermal relaxation in unimolecular chemical reactions<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#anormalous-thermal-relaxation-in-unimolecular-chemical-reactions"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Mpemba effect: hotter water freeze faster than cold water</p>
<h3 id="perturbation-spreading-in-a-non-reciprocal-classical-isotropic-magnet"><a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/N08/10" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Perturbation spreading in a non-reciprocal classical isotropic magnet</a><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#perturbation-spreading-in-a-non-reciprocal-classical-isotropic-magnet"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>totally absent-minded</p>
<h3 id="stefan-maxwell-diffusivities-of-gas-mixtures-and-liqiud-electrolytes-from-oxford">Stefan-Maxwell diffusivities of gas mixtures and liqiud electrolytes from Oxford<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#stefan-maxwell-diffusivities-of-gas-mixtures-and-liqiud-electrolytes-from-oxford"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>electrolytes, concentrated solution theory: Gibbs-Duhem relations</p>
<p>very math heavy, and words too small on slides. presentation visualization not so good.</p>
<p>extended DFN model</p>
<p>Onager’s regression</p>
<h2 id="q04-non-equilibrium-thermodynamics-from-chemical-reaction-networks-to-natural-selection-ii">Q04: Non-equilibrium Thermodynamics: From Chemical Reaction Networks to Natural Selection II<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#q04-non-equilibrium-thermodynamics-from-chemical-reaction-networks-to-natural-selection-ii"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="free-energy-transduction-chemical-reaction-network">Free energy transduction, chemical reaction network<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#free-energy-transduction-chemical-reaction-network"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>non-linear reaction: at least second order reaction</p>
<p>reactions → emergent cycles</p>
<h3 id="scaling-relations-of-energy-dissipation-rate-in-non-quilibrium-reaction-systems">Scaling relations of energy dissipation rate in non-quilibrium reaction systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#scaling-relations-of-energy-dissipation-rate-in-non-quilibrium-reaction-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>state space renormalization group</p>
<h3 id="algebra-on-biological-structures-caltech-and-cold-spring-harbor">algebra on biological structures, Caltech and Cold Spring Harbor<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#algebra-on-biological-structures-caltech-and-cold-spring-harbor"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>second quantization, field operators in multiparticle Fock space</p>
<p>classic particles in quantum language</p>
<p>the operation is the Wick contraction</p>
<h3 id="decomposing-local-arrow-of-time-interacting-systems">decomposing, local arrow of time, interacting systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#decomposing-local-arrow-of-time-interacting-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>$\dot I = D_{KL}[P(x\rightarrow x')||P(x'\rightarrow x)]$</p>
<p>“entropy production” again: Prigogine 1947, Shcnakenberg 1976, Skinner Dunkel 2021</p>
<p>observe k elements in the system: interaction irreversibility $\dot I^{(k)}_{int}=\dot I^{(k)} - \dot I^{(k-1)}$</p>
<h3 id="information-transmission-by-heterogeneous-cell-populations">information transmission by heterogeneous cell populations<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#information-transmission-by-heterogeneous-cell-populations"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>noise can ruin cellular info sensing</p>
<p>individual cell senses better than population(?) <strong>conditional mutual information</strong> reflects this</p>
<h3 id="functional-universality-microbial-thermodynamic-constraints">functional universality, microbial, thermodynamic constraints<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#functional-universality-microbial-thermodynamic-constraints"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>energy-limited vs. nutrient limited</p>
<h3 id="trade-off">trade off:<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#trade-off"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>law of energy in biology; model organism being anaerobes B. theta</p>
<p>PPi (pyrophorsphate) as energy source</p>
<h3 id="3d-diffusion-in-ecoli">3D diffusion in E.coli<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#3d-diffusion-in-ecoli"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h2 id="physics-of-social-interactions-ii">Physics of social interactions II<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#physics-of-social-interactions-ii"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>firefly, one research about vocabulary, one about spatiotemporal pattern</p>
<p>bunblebees, SLEAP to identity action and track</p>
<p>ant, fire ant, BOBbots, multi-occupancy lattice gas, rule based model→observed result</p>
<p>social polarization: vector force, but how agents are embedded into this space? no answer</p>
<p>HKB system, third party induced bistability, symmetry breaking “HOW”!</p>
<p><strong>Team formation</strong>: <a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/S03/9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Modeling the Catalysis of Collaboration at In-Person and Virtual Conferences</a>: Non-linear memory model, scialog dataset</p>
<p>mirror game: no designated leader experts reach higher accuracy and velocities</p>
<p>Granger causality analysis: not so advertised. experiment with flow switch. Presentation not so well given.</p>
<p>Bacteria reshape their surroundings to enable migration: use bioprinting. different pore size in media. non-motile vs. motile. motile E.coli can escape tight pores</p>
<h2 id="learning-dynamical-models-across-physical-systems"><strong>Learning dynamical models across physical systems</strong><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#learning-dynamical-models-across-physical-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="learning-dominant-physical-processes-with-data-driven-balance-models-walking"><strong>Learning dominant physical processes with data-driven balance models (walking)</strong><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#learning-dominant-physical-processes-with-data-driven-balance-models-walking"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<ul>
<li>obtain kinetics without markers
<ul>
<li>2d median filter, viterbi filter</li>
<li><strong>anipose</strong>: combination of  2d filters, triangulation, minimize spatiotemporal variation in limb length</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>feedback model
<ul>
<li>reflex model, central pattern generator</li>
<li>tune the sensor neurons with laser</li>
<li>proprioceptor model → state estimator → neural controller → (muscle model)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="knodes-to-learn-complex-dynamics-and-chaos-by-m-ani-hsieh-from-upenn">KNODES to learn complex dynamics and chaos by M. Ani Hsieh from UPenn<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#knodes-to-learn-complex-dynamics-and-chaos-by-m-ani-hsieh-from-upenn"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ocean data</li>
<li>neural ordinary differential equation (NODE).
<ul>
<li>NeurIPS 6572-6583, 2018</li>
<li>knowledge embedding enabled by NODEs. Knowledge-based learning of nonlinear dynamics and chaos. Chaos vol31. 2021</li>
<li>applied to Hopf model, Stiff Can Der Pol model,</li>
<li>inferring swarming dynamics from data</li>
<li>deformable image registration</li>
<li>model predictive control that controlled drones</li>
<li>learning chaos</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>scalar.seas.upenn.edu</p>
<h3 id="physics-of-behaviors-across-scales">physics of behaviors across scales<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#physics-of-behaviors-across-scales"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>large scale behavior (trajectory): variation explained by exploration-exploitation</p>
<p>fine scale (posture): decompose into 5 primitive postures</p>
<p>connection:</p>
<ul>
<li>transfer operators → slow emergent variables, subsume nonlinear to linear</li>
<li>use time series to max predict system to compensate missing d.o.f</li>
</ul>
<p>“hopping dynamics” again</p>
<p>non-ergodic drives that prevent the dynamics from relaxing to the steady state within measurement time</p>
<p>the landscape the worms seeking food is also time dependent</p>
<h3 id="ml-for-biomechanics">ML for biomechanics<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#ml-for-biomechanics"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>this group’s interested is very scattered.</p>
<p>first part just missed: learn macroscopic params in hydrodynamics as fields</p>
<p>Unet to predict some cell protein density, identify relevant signals</p>
<p>model: Oakes et al, BioPhys J 2014</p>
<p>fruit fly tissue</p>
<p>physics-informed machine learning again</p>
<h3 id="physics-informed-machine-learning-climate-modeling-and-covid-19-forecasting">physics-informed machine learning: climate modeling and COVID 19 forecasting<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#physics-informed-machine-learning-climate-modeling-and-covid-19-forecasting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Unet also here. turbulent-flow net. basically a new network structure based on unet.</p>
<p>group equivariance leads to another net called Scale Equ-ResNet in order to retrieve symmetry</p>
<p>spatial-temporal neural p...: Baysian Active Learning</p>
<h2 id="collective-behavior-in-biology">Collective Behavior in Biology<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#collective-behavior-in-biology"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="thermal-trp-channels-of-vipers">thermal TRP channels of vipers<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#thermal-trp-channels-of-vipers"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>1K sensitivity of a channel; 1mK sensitivity of neurons</p>
<p>independent channels, over time of several independent measurements</p>
<p>hypothesis: TRPA1 channels are embedded into a dynamical system near bifurcation. activated channels activates other channels</p>
<p>question: does coupling break the independence of measurements? single channel info is ~1</p>
<h3 id="growth-difference-in-single-and-multicellular-organisms">growth difference in single and multicellular organisms<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#growth-difference-in-single-and-multicellular-organisms"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>expanding epithelium,when the area grows linearly, the size only ~$\sqrt{a}$, does this feedback to cells?</p>
<p>cells divide at a smaller size</p>
<p>lower bound of cellular size might come from genome size. CCND1labels DNA demage</p>
<p>no mechanisms yet</p>
<h3 id="collective-signal-oscillation">collective signal oscillation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#collective-signal-oscillation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>a lot of models</p>
<p>key features not heard clearly. adaptive spiking</p>
<h3 id="cellular-migration-on-substrate-with-topological-defects">cellular migration on substrate with topological defects<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cellular-migration-on-substrate-with-topological-defects"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>the way they defined topology number = -1 is not as my expectation</p>
<p>Francesca Serra group experiment</p>
<p>not too much work</p>
<h3 id="synchrony-and-causality">synchrony and causality<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#synchrony-and-causality"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Bo Sun again. granger causality again</p>
<p>used a famous model not written down. Sounded like Nagumo model</p>
<h3 id="living-chiral-crystals">living chiral crystals<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#living-chiral-crystals"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>starfish embryos</p>
<h3 id="central-nervous-system">central nervous system<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#central-nervous-system"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>gut motions and nerves in crafish</p>
<p>just using 5-HT is not enough to compensate the cutting of nerve</p>
<h3 id="role-of-position-info-in-collcetive-gradient-sensing">role of position info in collcetive gradient sensing<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#role-of-position-info-in-collcetive-gradient-sensing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Cramer-Rao bound by maximum likelihood estimation</p>
<p>benchmark was called tug-of-war model</p>
<p>contact inhibition of locomotion</p>
<h3 id="self-tuned-criticality-amplifies-signals-in-bacterial-chemotaxis">self-tuned criticality amplifies signals in bacterial chemotaxis<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#self-tuned-criticality-amplifies-signals-in-bacterial-chemotaxis"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>E.coli chemosensing: high cooperativity, perfect adaptation, large noise</p>
<p>symmetric spreading of CheA</p>
<h3 id="division-migration-cell-signaling">division, migration, cell signaling<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#division-migration-cell-signaling"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>MDCK monolayer</p>
<p>very biology heavy</p>
<p>a low fluctuation phase</p>
<h3 id="criticality-in-cochlea">criticality in Cochlea<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#criticality-in-cochlea"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>impedance = pressure/height, WKB approximation</p>
<p>hair cells are the sensors, undergo Hopf bifurcation</p>
<h3 id="defining-success-for-pairwise-maximum-entropy-models">defining success for pairwise maximum entropy models<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#defining-success-for-pairwise-maximum-entropy-models"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>mouse brain hippocampus, 2000 neurons</p>
<p>in subgroups, swap 1/2 of the cells to minimize pairwise correlation coefficient</p>
<h2 id="stoichastic-thermodynamics-and-biological-and-artificial-info-processing">stoichastic thermodynamics and biological and artificial info processing<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#stoichastic-thermodynamics-and-biological-and-artificial-info-processing"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="entropy-generation-during-computation---is-it-really-avoidable-even-in-principle"><a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/Y09/1" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Entropy generation during computation - is it really avoidable, even in principle?</a><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#entropy-generation-during-computation---is-it-really-avoidable-even-in-principle"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p><a href="https://march.aps.org/sessions/Y09/1" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Entropy generation during computation</a>: Szilard’s argument</p>
<p>erase and copy operation of ribonsome works like a universal turing machine.</p>
<p>in theory, logically irreversible process can be thermodynamically reversible, like <strong>erasure</strong></p>
<h3 id="statistic-thermodynamics-of-communication-channels">statistic thermodynamics of communication channels<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#statistic-thermodynamics-of-communication-channels"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>MIT media lab</p>
<p>$\sigma(\vec x_f)\leftrightarrow DK(P(\vec x_f)||P(\vec x))$ KL Divergence</p>
<p>2 models, 3 by 3 nodes with some lines connecting some pairs, didn’ get what they mean.</p>
<p>they call the thing NESS (non equilibrium steady state).</p>
<p>takehome: dissipative not monotuned increasing as info transmission increases. some channel more efficient than others</p>
<h3 id="fluid-intellengence-activities-from-learning-and-forgetting">fluid intellengence: activities from learning and forgetting<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#fluid-intellengence-activities-from-learning-and-forgetting"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>diameter variable particles as intelligent agents</p>
<p>diameter function $D(\vec p)$ symmetry determines symmetry of new distribution</p>
<p>policy optimization, reinforce learning to search behavior space</p>
<h3 id="nonquilibrium-dynamics-of-temporally-responsive-single-molecular-automation">nonquilibrium dynamics of temporally responsive, single molecular automation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#nonquilibrium-dynamics-of-temporally-responsive-single-molecular-automation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>smart vs. inert: ability to perform temporal pattern recognition</p>
<p>a polymer that has multiple foldable positions.</p>
<p>dual scale master equation</p>
<h3 id="thermodynamics-of-biological-signal-propagation">thermodynamics of biological signal propagation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#thermodynamics-of-biological-signal-propagation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>information: $lim_{T\rightarrow \infin}\frac{1}{T}\int MI(I,O)dt$</p>
<p>diffusion of signal,some equations, etc, parameters include size of source and receiver</p>
<p>implications:</p>
<ul>
<li>cells don’t talk because they are too small</li>
<li>E.coli phosphotases are close to ion channels (missed, not sure)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="dissipation-accuracy-speed-tradeoffs-in-computation-on-attice-self-assembly">dissipation-accuracy-speed tradeoffs in computation on-;attice self-assembly<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#dissipation-accuracy-speed-tradeoffs-in-computation-on-attice-self-assembly"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Landauer principle</p>
<p>D. Woods. Nature 2019</p>
<p>diamond shape 2-in2-out tiles that</p>
<h3 id="bayesian-mechanics-for-interacting-systems">Bayesian mechanics for interacting systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#bayesian-mechanics-for-interacting-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Langevin equation</p>
<p>NESS again</p>
<h3 id="wipe-a-bit-with-no-energy-cost-by-pypassing-liouville-theorem">wipe a bit with no energy cost by pypassing Liouville theorem<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#wipe-a-bit-with-no-energy-cost-by-pypassing-liouville-theorem"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Liouville says Halmitonian system must be incompressible in phase space</p>
<p>$H_{ers} = H_0+gH_{contraction}$</p>
<p>micro-canonical energy shell</p>
<h3 id="stochastic-thermodynamics-of-finite-automata"><strong>Stochastic Thermodynamics of Finite Automata</strong><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#stochastic-thermodynamics-of-finite-automata"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>not following, deterministic finite automata</p>
<h3 id="nonequilibrium-thermodynamics-of-uncertain-stochastic-processes"><strong>Nonequilibrium thermodynamics of uncertain stochastic processes</strong><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#nonequilibrium-thermodynamics-of-uncertain-stochastic-processes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>wanted to follow but failed</p>
<h3 id="glycan-function-of-golgi-constrain-its-morphology">glycan, function of Golgi constrain its morphology<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#glycan-function-of-golgi-constrain-its-morphology"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>also used KL divergence here.</p>
<p>looks like there has been no experiment, maybe I missed it.</p>
<h3 id="stochastic-thermodynamics-of-anomalous-diffusion-generated-by-scaled-and-fractional-brownian-motions"><strong>Stochastic thermodynamics of anomalous diffusion generated by scaled and fractional Brownian motions</strong><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#stochastic-thermodynamics-of-anomalous-diffusion-generated-by-scaled-and-fractional-brownian-motions"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Stochastic thermodynamics: ST</p>
<p>fractional Brownian motion: fractional gaussian noise (no idea what)</p>
<p>fluctuation-dissipation is broken by memory in noise</p>
<h3 id="optimality-in-biological-proofreading"><strong>Optimality in biological proofreading</strong><a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#optimality-in-biological-proofreading"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>DNA replication error rate 10^-8 ~10^-10</p>
<p>experiment K_D/K_C = 10^-2, observed error rate 10^-3~10^-4, discrepancy</p>
<p>Pareto optimal fronts of kinetic proofreading</p>
<p><strong>generalized Hopfield model</strong></p>
<p>speed-dissipation trade off again</p>
<h2 id="dynamics-in-evolution">Dynamics in Evolution<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#dynamics-in-evolution"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="multicellular">Multicellular<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#multicellular"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Size→nutrition gradient→differentiation</p>
<p>Multicellular yeast! T yeast</p>
<p>Bozdag</p>
<p>Non-reformable→mechanical challenge</p>
<p>The aspect ratio increases significantly after the size grows</p>
<p>Aggregation not happening; Tangling spans the bulk</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.tex | Notes during APS March Meeting 2023 in Las Vegas]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/notes-during-APS-march-meeting-2023-Las-Vegas</link>
            <guid>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/notes-during-APS-march-meeting-2023-Las-Vegas</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes during APS March Meeting 2023 in Las Vegas]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some interesting sessions:</p>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-5FB0A373-E7B7-45FF-97A5-81F9392CBB02.jpeg" alt="5FB0A373-E7B7-45FF-97A5-81F9392CBB02.jpeg"><figcaption>5FB0A373-E7B7-45FF-97A5-81F9392CBB02.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-E35F718E-38ED-432D-AC00-44E8D8893CC6.jpeg" alt="E35F718E-38ED-432D-AC00-44E8D8893CC6.jpeg"><figcaption>E35F718E-38ED-432D-AC00-44E8D8893CC6.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-A44D0789-44CC-42F5-85D1-E0CA93952712.jpeg" alt="A44D0789-44CC-42F5-85D1-E0CA93952712.jpeg"><figcaption>A44D0789-44CC-42F5-85D1-E0CA93952712.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-7E0D2844-3BC8-4BEF-BABA-2818EEBA2C15.jpeg" alt="7E0D2844-3BC8-4BEF-BABA-2818EEBA2C15.jpeg"><figcaption>7E0D2844-3BC8-4BEF-BABA-2818EEBA2C15.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-A727558B-D110-48A1-B125-67A7067BFBD5.jpeg" alt="A727558B-D110-48A1-B125-67A7067BFBD5.jpeg"><figcaption>A727558B-D110-48A1-B125-67A7067BFBD5.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-B635604C-B9BD-4A34-9767-AD7338A80765.jpeg" alt="B635604C-B9BD-4A34-9767-AD7338A80765.jpeg"><figcaption>B635604C-B9BD-4A34-9767-AD7338A80765.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<h2 id="network-theory-and-application-to-complex-systems">Network theory and application to complex systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#network-theory-and-application-to-complex-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>1st talk: <strong>Avalanches Dynamics</strong> and its critical points, cortes dynamics, very long, missed first ~10 minutes, hard to follow, coarse grained 朗道-金斯堡 theory</p>
<p>Fokker-Planck equation, Fourier expansions, use as parameters of ____, choose a closure to solve</p>
<h2 id="machine-learning-in-complex-systems">Machine learning in complex systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#machine-learning-in-complex-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>Fractional nn for continuous modeling of complex fluids: Caputo method for fractional derivative</p>
<p>Inferring forces in many-particle systems using physics tailored ml: Chinese student with Ilya from Emory. Bruckner 2021 PNAS, cell. His work, dusty plasma, non reciprocal. Mutual Interactions, with environment, linear damping. not clear details of the nn</p>
<p>Echo state network: Arizona state, Chinese student. A branch of reservoir learning. Switching states not always successful. Bad presentation. Don’t even know what question he is learning with this nn. Could be Lorenz system</p>
<p>Hopper Flow: particles passing a narrow gate in 2d. Classify problem: flow, clogging, clogged, empty arch. Direct interpretability: linear SVM.</p>
<p>Committer of Reactive Events in and out of equilibrium: UCB. Variational methods for time-dependent backward Kolmogorov equation. decompose rate into contributions from different degrees of freedom.</p>
<p>Predict Microfluid properties with ML: oil droplets into water, predict the droplet size. Monodispensed phse, poly  (jetting). Pretty small network and small dataset. nice GUI</p>
<p>ML for inverse design of metameterial. Combinatory/Discrete, imbalance. building block → unit cell → metamaterial. Ogliomodes</p>
<p>Long-term behavior with liearn regression. Moody 1944 moody diagram. Studied Lorenz system. Use short trajetories to predict long term properties. Period orbit theory</p>
<h2 id="quantitative-cell-physiology-i---shape-and-size">Quantitative cell physiology I - shape and size<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#quantitative-cell-physiology-i---shape-and-size"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>missed 1st talk for breakfast.</p>
<h3 id="beyond-g1s-regulation-how-cell-size-homeostasis-is-tightly-controlled-throughout-the-cell-cycle">Beyond G1/S regulation: how cell size homeostasis is tightly controlled throughout the cell cycle?<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#beyond-g1s-regulation-how-cell-size-homeostasis-is-tightly-controlled-throughout-the-cell-cycle"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>G1/S not the main control cell size variation; CV reduces across cell cycle</p>
<p>rate positively correlated to size, but not exponential. this should lead to different mass density, but it is maintained tightly stable.</p>
<h3 id="cell-cycle-dependent-growth-regulation-in-bacteria">Cell cycle dependent growth regulation in bacteria.<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cell-cycle-dependent-growth-regulation-in-bacteria"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>data  show that E. Coli cell growth is super-exponential.</p>
<p>model: ribonsome growth is exponential,</p>
<p>B. Subtilis growth rate is not monotonic</p>
<p>Scott, M, 2014 Mol Sys Bio</p>
<p>tome averaged mass function and allocation function are equivalent.</p>
<p>A model, but didn’t see how it’s correlated to cell-cycle</p>
<h3 id="e-coli-coordination-of-cell-dimensions-to-preserve-macromolecular-densities-between-compartments">E. Coli coordination of cell dimensions to preserve macromolecular densities between compartments<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#e-coli-coordination-of-cell-dimensions-to-preserve-macromolecular-densities-between-compartments"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>shape is also important, not just dimensions.</p>
<p>periplasm is the region between inner and outer membrane of E. Coli. Its colume fraction scales differently with the width and length of the cell</p>
<p>measure periplasm density by shocking and destroying the outer membrane and measure protein amount</p>
<p>cell aspect ratio is relatively controlled by changing periplasm biomass fraction and average cell width. Testified in multiple mutants</p>
<p>Growth rate is not a control parameter</p>
<h3 id="molecular-noise-on-cellular-growth">Molecular noise on cellular growth<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#molecular-noise-on-cellular-growth"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>standard model of size homeostasis: timer, adder, sizer</p>
<p>consider noise, get lower bound of size</p>
<h3 id="dynamic-proteome-trade-offs-regulate-cell-size-and-growth-in-fluctuating-nutrient-conditions">Dynamic proteome trade-offs regulate cell size and growth in fluctuating nutrient conditions<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#dynamic-proteome-trade-offs-regulate-cell-size-and-growth-in-fluctuating-nutrient-conditions"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>growth rate and size control; in fluctuating nutritions, there is overshoot</p>
<p>assums: cell maximize flux; division protein co-regulated with metabolic sector</p>
<p>model predicts cells prioritize division over biomass accumulation durign downshift</p>
<h3 id="simulation-about-mechanical-properties-of-peptidoglycan-pg">Simulation about mechanical properties of Peptidoglycan (PG)<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#simulation-about-mechanical-properties-of-peptidoglycan-pg"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>University of Jena, Balance of the Microverse. Very technical, very detailed</p>
<h3 id="teichoic-acids-as-organizing-center-of-growth-in-b-subtilis">Teichoic acids as organizing center of growth in B. Subtilis<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#teichoic-acids-as-organizing-center-of-growth-in-b-subtilis"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>inhibiting its synthesis immediately loses the cells’ rod shape; fluorescent images are uniform across the whole cell.</p>
<p>perturbing synthesis causes growth rate shutdown after loss of rod shape</p>
<p>PonA mediated crosslinking is required for growth in the absence of wall teichoic acids</p>
<p>proposed a model, not quantitative, seems not testified.</p>
<h3 id="coarse-grained-cell-wall-simulation">coarse grained cell wall simulation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#coarse-grained-cell-wall-simulation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>turgor pressure: 膨胀压</p>
<p>anisotropic deformability</p>
<p>surface evolver</p>
<h3 id="nanostrctural-changes-of-peptidoglycan">Nanostrctural changes of Peptidoglycan<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#nanostrctural-changes-of-peptidoglycan"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Penicillin binds enzymes with the last step of PG synthesis.</p>
<p>treat with mecillinam; use AFM, changes local molecule orientation &#x26; PG organization</p>
<p>gaps in the PG network, not orientation, caused the death</p>
<h3 id="robustness-and-fragility-in-yeast">Robustness and Fragility in Yeast<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#robustness-and-fragility-in-yeast"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Umap for metabolome data</p>
<h3 id="how-type-1-fimbriae-help-e-coli-adhere-to-interfaces">How Type 1 Fimbriae Help E. coli Adhere to Interfaces?<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#how-type-1-fimbriae-help-e-coli-adhere-to-interfaces"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>What is a fimbriae in bacteria?</p>
<p>Thin,  hairlike appendages, 1 to 20 microns in length and often occurring in large numbers, present on the cells of gram-negative bacteria, particularly Enterobacteriaceae and Neisseria.</p>
<p>they contruct mutants and can both adhere and swim.</p>
<h3 id="zno-kills-bacteria">ZnO kills bacteria<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#zno-kills-bacteria"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Hypothezes: metal ion production, generation of reactive oxide</p>
<h2 id="march-7-2023-ecological-dynamics">March 7, 2023 Ecological Dynamics<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#march-7-2023-ecological-dynamics"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p><strong>Spatial drug heterogeneity:</strong> a row of multiple wells, some of them have drugs. Mean field survival criterion: <strong><span class="katex"><span class="katex-mathml"><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>L</mi><mo>=</mo><mi>π</mi><msqrt><mrow></mrow></msqrt></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">L=\pi\sqrt{}</annotation></semantics></math></span><span class="katex-html" aria-hidden="true"><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:0.6833em;"></span><span class="mord mathnormal">L</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2778em;"></span><span class="mrel">=</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2778em;"></span></span><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:1.04em;vertical-align:-0.2395em;"></span><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.03588em;">π</span><span class="mord sqrt"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.8005em;"><span class="svg-align" style="top:-3em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="mord" style="padding-left:0.833em;"></span></span><span style="top:-2.7605em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="hide-tail" style="min-width:0.853em;height:1.08em;"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="400em" height="1.08em" viewBox="0 0 400000 1080" preserveAspectRatio="xMinYMin slice"><path d="M95,702
c-2.7,0,-7.17,-2.7,-13.5,-8c-5.8,-5.3,-9.5,-10,-9.5,-14
c0,-2,0.3,-3.3,1,-4c1.3,-2.7,23.83,-20.7,67.5,-54
c44.2,-33.3,65.8,-50.3,66.5,-51c1.3,-1.3,3,-2,5,-2c4.7,0,8.7,3.3,12,10
s173,378,173,378c0.7,0,35.3,-71,104,-213c68.7,-142,137.5,-285,206.5,-429
c69,-144,104.5,-217.7,106.5,-221
l0 -0
c5.3,-9.3,12,-14,20,-14
H400000v40H845.2724
s-225.272,467,-225.272,467s-235,486,-235,486c-2.7,4.7,-9,7,-19,7
c-6,0,-10,-1,-12,-3s-194,-422,-194,-422s-65,47,-65,47z
M834 80h400000v40h-400000z"></path></svg></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.2395em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></strong>, and beyond mean field (some purtubation theory borrowed from quantum to reaction diffusion equation).</p>
<h3 id="evo-adaptation-on-cell-shape-by-katie">Evo adaptation on cell shape by Katie<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#evo-adaptation-on-cell-shape-by-katie"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>mechanical factors give same-fitness cells different growth rates in a colony. cells labels with 2 colors of fluorescence and grow in a mixed colony</p>
<p>mechanical forces slows down natural selection, both directions</p>
<p>used yeasts and grow for 10 days. select edge and center and continue growing. center still similar, but edge cells become elongated. “The elongation is a mechanism to get out of nitrogen starvation”(?)</p>
<p>sequenced ancester, center, and edge cells. Found 9 genes</p>

<p><strong>The fate of beneficial and deleterious mutations in range expansions driven by long-range dispersal:</strong> luckiest better than fittest, spatial factors dominate.</p>
<p><strong>Speciation at an expanding front</strong>: superdiffusion → stepping stone model. Want to explain how homogeneous population evolve into species→ fitness model</p>
<h3 id="f13-emerging-principles-and-new-developments-in-non-equilibrium-thermodynamics-natural-selection-and-chemical-reaction-networks---nonequilibrium-thermodynamics-of-chemical-reaction-networks">F13: Emerging Principles and New Developments in Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics, Natural Selection and Chemical Reaction Networks - Nonequilibrium thermodynamics of chemical reaction networks<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#f13-emerging-principles-and-new-developments-in-non-equilibrium-thermodynamics-natural-selection-and-chemical-reaction-networks---nonequilibrium-thermodynamics-of-chemical-reaction-networks"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>CRN: chemical reaction networks, and this is about</p>
<p>circuit theory for CRN: arxiv-2210.08035</p>
<ul>
<li>modules do not share internal species</li>
<li>emergent cycles and effective reactions</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="203-cell-model">203 cell model<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#203-cell-model"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="active-transport-and-cell-self-organization">Active transport and Cell self organization<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#active-transport-and-cell-self-organization"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>A lot of microtubules</p>
<p>CCB-FL</p>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-214D3DB8-7A99-42AC-8C18-051171564D6D.jpeg" alt="214D3DB8-7A99-42AC-8C18-051171564D6D.jpeg"><figcaption>214D3DB8-7A99-42AC-8C18-051171564D6D.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<p>Steam flows in large cells B. Corti 1741, fruit fly oocyte</p>
<p>Flows in organelle positioning. Zidovska PNAS 2013, 2018. Gatlin lab U Wy</p>
<p>Microscopic mechanisms about micro tubules is ill understood</p>
<p>aLENS a living ensemble simulator</p>
<p>1model: Cytoplasm as confined Newtonian fluid</p>
<p>Another model: coarse grained stokes force: fruit fly oogenesis</p>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-C622BD7E-E638-4194-A563-096F73209132.jpeg" alt="C622BD7E-E638-4194-A563-096F73209132.jpeg"><figcaption>C622BD7E-E638-4194-A563-096F73209132.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<p>skellySim</p>
<h3 id="di-pierro-physical-genomics">Di Pierro: physical genomics<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#di-pierro-physical-genomics"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Nucleosome</p>
<p>but his title is <strong>Landscapes of Genomic Architecture Across Evolution</strong>, which is not</p>
<p>ideal chromsome: every time  2 loci at genomic distance d come into contact there is a gain/loss of free energy <span class="katex"><span class="katex-mathml"><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>γ</mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mi>d</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\gamma(d)</annotation></semantics></math></span><span class="katex-html" aria-hidden="true"><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:1em;vertical-align:-0.25em;"></span><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.05556em;">γ</span><span class="mopen">(</span><span class="mord mathnormal">d</span><span class="mclose">)</span></span></span></span></p>
<h3 id="stochastic-model-for-cell-survival-and-evolution">Stochastic model for cell survival and evolution<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#stochastic-model-for-cell-survival-and-evolution"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Single threshold and double threshold</p>
<h2 id="metabolism-and-growth">metabolism and growth<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#metabolism-and-growth"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="adaptability-and-sensitivities-in-gene-regulation-out-of-equilibrium">Adaptability and sensitivities in gene regulation out of equilibrium<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#adaptability-and-sensitivities-in-gene-regulation-out-of-equilibrium"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Spare able energy</p>
<p>Matrix tree theorem: inter alios</p>
<h3 id="biofilm-electric-shocked">biofilm electric shocked<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#biofilm-electric-shocked"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Bacteria use membrane potential to regulate bio processes: cell division, antibiotic resistance, metabolism</p>
<p>Electrical stimulation</p>
<p>Biofilm: B subtilis: motile cells and matrix forming cells</p>
<p>Accumulation of motile cells around electrodes</p>
<p>Proliferation or switch? Proliferate</p>
<h3 id="self-organization-waves-on-huge-single-cell-living-on-light">Self organization waves on huge single cell living on light<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#self-organization-waves-on-huge-single-cell-living-on-light"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>external driving force main  reason?</p>
<p>Also internal limit cycle?</p>
<h3 id="crisper-array-for-e-coli-under-antibiotic-exposure">CRISPER array for E. coli under antibiotic exposure<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#crisper-array-for-e-coli-under-antibiotic-exposure"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>crisper cas 12-a</p>
<p>Beta Score , different in different media</p>
<h3 id="zno-nano-particles-on-bacteria-in-magnetic-field">ZnO Nano particles on bacteria in magnetic field<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#zno-nano-particles-on-bacteria-in-magnetic-field"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Gram staining</p>
<p>Synopsys quantumatk</p>
<h2 id="ecological-dynamics">ecological dynamics<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#ecological-dynamics"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="design-microbial-community">design microbial community<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#design-microbial-community"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Goal: metabolite production &#x26; degradation; pathogen inhibit</p>
<p>Emerge,</p>
<p>function as a design problem = f(composition)</p>
<p>Trivial idea: open the hood and see the interaction</p>
<p>Another way: borrow from molecular level: how sequences gives function</p>
<p>Statistical design: blue and red fluorescent proteins, separated by 13 amino acids, fit color as 13d binary</p>
<p>Success because landscape simple</p>
<p>Ecology: if one can predict function from presence absence of a strain</p>
<p>Absence =-1 not 0, for similarity with Frourier expansion</p>
<p>500 communities of 27 strains, predict production of a chemical</p>
<p>sampling a very small space but result good, (predict/true value diagram)</p>
<p>Also predicted biomass (OD)</p>
<p>Additive property is the key to success</p>
<p>Can get explained variance by the order of</p>
<p>Ruggedness/slope</p>
<p>Compare with Generalized Lotka-Volterra</p>
<p>Metabolic cascades makes landscape rugged.</p>
<h3 id="connecting-global-patterns-to-ecological-processes">connecting global patterns to ecological processes<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#connecting-global-patterns-to-ecological-processes"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Global soil samples</p>
<p>Environmental filtering cannot explain some of their data</p>
<p>Emerges from interactions</p>
<h3 id="mapping-prediction-error-versus-information-content-of-coarse-grained-descriptions-of-microbial-ecosystems">Mapping prediction error versus information content of coarse-grained descriptions of microbial ecosystems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mapping-prediction-error-versus-information-content-of-coarse-grained-descriptions-of-microbial-ecosystems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Jacob moran</p>
<p>Framework to compare different coarse grained descriptions: partitioning, error-information diagram</p>
<p>To distinguish mechanisms of emergent simplicity: diversity in the partition</p>
<h2 id="materials-that-work-by-themselves">Materials that work by themselves<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#materials-that-work-by-themselves"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="biotic-and-abiotic">biotic and abiotic<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#biotic-and-abiotic"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Adaptive d spring</p>
<h2 id="pattern-formation">Pattern Formation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#pattern-formation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>missed 1st talk of 30 min</p>
<h3 id="morphoelastic-growth-to-model-aortic-geometry">Morphoelastic growth to model aortic geometry<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#morphoelastic-growth-to-model-aortic-geometry"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>aortic 主动脉</p>
<p>integrated gaussian curvature</p>
<p>AI/ML needs a lot of data, so they need explicit models</p>
<p>NHLBI: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute</p>
<h3 id="experimental-on-chaos-in-cardiac-tissue">experimental on chaos in cardiac tissue<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#experimental-on-chaos-in-cardiac-tissue"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>kept in Tyrode solution</p>
<p>action potential duration + diastolic interval = period</p>
<p>TISEAN (a <a href="https://www.pks.mpg.de/tisean/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nonlinear Time Series Analysis</a> tool) to get Lyapunov exponent</p>
<h3 id="excitability-at-interface">excitability at interface<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#excitability-at-interface"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>2 bio-electric tissues, one only sodium channels, the other only potasium channels. so no spikes on their own. then shed laser on them.</p>
<p>A as fast variable, B as slow variable. A is x^3 shaped, whie B is -x shaped, then</p>
<p>can also exlpain BZ reaction with some sub-reactions separated, and lumberjack and forect and desert</p>
<h3 id="light-induced-cortical-excitability">light induced cortical excitability<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#light-induced-cortical-excitability"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>shape control strategy in meiotic starfish oocytes.</p>
<p>rho protein. part of some signaling pathway, kymographs</p>
<p>seems to be my competitor on postdoc project in MPI-PKS</p>
<p>pole to pole opto-GEF accumulation aymmetry</p>
<p>presentation overtimed, not well delievered</p>

<p><strong>Exploring regular, exotic and turbulent flow states in active fluids via the framework of Exact Coherent Structures</strong>: too fast, totally lost. Who tm knows what is shadowing</p>
<h3 id="pattern-plant-roots">Pattern plant roots<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#pattern-plant-roots"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>tropism 向性: gravitropism, phototropism</p>
<p>roots on obstacles: skewing, coiling, waving</p>
<p>numerical scheme: separation of timescles, derivatives of intrinsic curvature over time, against cross section growth rate gradient.</p>
<p>decoupling the tropic dynamics parallel and perpendicular to the slope.</p>
<p>each curing given an energy, can predict transition between states</p>
<p>skewing is different, seen in mutants. It’s the intrinsic twist</p>
<h3 id="cdc42-mobility-changes-yeast-shape-and-survival">cdc42 mobility changes yeast shape and survival<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cdc42-mobility-changes-yeast-shape-and-survival"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>As title says</p>
<h3 id="jagged-ligand-improves-notch-signaling">Jagged ligand improves notch signaling<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#jagged-ligand-improves-notch-signaling"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Notch, delta, jagged</p>
<h2 id="synthetic-biology">Synthetic biology<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#synthetic-biology"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="stochastic-model-selex">stochastic model SELEX<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#stochastic-model-selex"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>to select aptamers with highest affinity : <a href="https://www.basepairbio.com/what-is-an-aptamer/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://www.basepairbio.com/what-is-an-aptamer/</a></p>
<p>Optimal policy: A1 A2>>T, T>>1</p>
<h3 id="cytoplasm-is-organized-crowding">Cytoplasm is organized, crowding<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cytoplasm-is-organized-crowding"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Crowded with macromolecules</p>
<p>Crowding of cell free gene expression change noise; simulations</p>
<p>Crowding gives attraction to membrane</p>
<p>Simulations</p>
<p>Impacts transcription and translation in cell-sized vesicles</p>
<h3 id="elisa-from-cornell--titrable-in-vivo-cre-loxp-in-e-coli">Elisa from Cornell : titrable in vivo Cre-loxP in E. coli<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#elisa-from-cornell--titrable-in-vivo-cre-loxp-in-e-coli"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Somatic differentiation</p>
<p>Er binding site, beta estradiol</p>
<p>DH10B RepOrter yfp</p>
<h2 id="research-in-germany">Research in Germany<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#research-in-germany"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="mpi">MPI<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mpi"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Write emails with info from website</p>
<p>humburg scholarship</p>
<p>6+2 years super generous funding enough to hire 2 postdoctoral, to early scholars</p>
<p>Foreigners 9 years after doctor degree has to be employed, so many leaves</p>
<p>University and Scores important, papers slow so not so important</p>
<p>DPG MEETING</p>
<p>140 directors, each has a way of sponsoring</p>
<p>Andrew Mackenzie</p>
<p>Go for Nobel prize, not professorship</p>
<p>Want to hire people with 20 yers of career left</p>
<p>Six months danger period, then 3 years safe</p>
<h3 id="cell-fate-transition">Cell fate transition<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cell-fate-transition"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h3 id="cell-type-order-parameters">cell type order parameters<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cell-type-order-parameters"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Saw last year</p>
<p>Order parameters:</p>
<p>scTop python package</p>
<h3 id="class-iv-da-neurons-laval-development">Class IV da neurons Laval development<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#class-iv-da-neurons-laval-development"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Macroscopic measurable: dendrite Densities, front velocity</p>
<p>Dendrite grow in stochastic manner</p>
<p>Mean field descriptions: grow, shrinking, stall states</p>
<p>master equations</p>
<p>Very in detail</p>
<p>Yale integrated graduate program in physical and engineering biology</p>
<h3 id="synnotch-expression-in-fruit-fly">synNotch expression in fruit fly<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#synnotch-expression-in-fruit-fly"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Delta notch: contact based intercellular signaling</p>
<p>Vortex based model framework</p>
<h2 id="intracellular-transport-and-organization">Intracellular transport and organization<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#intracellular-transport-and-organization"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="super-resolution">super resolution<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#super-resolution"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>STORM, PALM, FPALM, all in 2006</p>
<p>Correlative live cell and super resolution microscopy</p>
<p>Post translation modification: Tyrosinated/detyrosinated, de- is important , sparse and stochastic</p>
<p>De- VASH interact with MT</p>
<p>Mean square displacement analysis</p>
<p>Simulation:</p>
<h3 id="in-vitro-experiment-of-microtubules">In vitro experiment of Microtubules<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#in-vitro-experiment-of-microtubules"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<h2 id="switch-and-detach-at-intersections-of-microtubules">switch and detach at intersections of microtubules<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#switch-and-detach-at-intersections-of-microtubules"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>diaplacement≤path length, from experiment</p>
<h3 id="kinesin-123-bidirectional-transport">Kinesin-1,2,3, bidirectional transport<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#kinesin-123-bidirectional-transport"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Different detect rate</p>
<p>Kinesin compete for dynesin in a tug of war</p>
<p>segment analysis of slow trace</p>
<h3 id="motor">motor<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#motor"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>MTOC, convergence and target scretion of granules</p>
<p>Natural killer cells</p>
<h3 id="growth-of-axonal-caliber">Growth of axonal caliber<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#growth-of-axonal-caliber"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Axonal neurofilament as caliber modulators</p>
<p>Six state model Jung and Brown 2009, Li etc 2014</p>
<h3 id="intracellular-drug-transport-in-single-cell">intracellular drug transport in single cell<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#intracellular-drug-transport-in-single-cell"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Hoechst dye to measure effenciency</p>
<h3 id="alien-proteomics-diffusion-through-nuclear-pore">alien proteomics, diffusion through nuclear pore<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#alien-proteomics-diffusion-through-nuclear-pore"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Nuclear pore complex</p>
<p>FG-nucleoporin (IDR)</p>
<p>Active transport vs passive diffusion</p>
<p>\Delta F(R)</p>
<p>Inject frog oocyte into E. coli</p>
<h3 id="cone-shaped-hiv-capsid-through-nuclear-pore-complex">cone shaped hiv capsid through nuclear pore complex<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cone-shaped-hiv-capsid-through-nuclear-pore-complex"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Free energy of nuclear protein</p>
<p>Narrow end enter first</p>
<h3 id="er-for-transport-calcium-ion">ER for transport Calcium ion<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#er-for-transport-calcium-ion"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Ca bound to high capacity buffer proteins in ER</p>
<p>locally release in spikes</p>
<p>Reaction-diffusion model for calcium and buffer proteins</p>
<p>local cytoplasm concentration</p>
<p>in ER Lumen: proteins spread super diffusively; active runs along tubules, from single particle trajectories</p>
<p>altering morphology by morphogen expression: Rtn3 overexpression; Atlastin knockout</p>
<h2 id="collective-behavior">collective behavior<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#collective-behavior"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="biofilmcellsmatrix">biofilm=cells+matrix<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#biofilmcellsmatrix"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>SPP2389- emergent function of bacterial multicellularity</p>
<p>Ng bacteria</p>
<h3 id="flow-dirven-cancer-cell-migration">flow-dirven cancer cell migration<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#flow-dirven-cancer-cell-migration"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>autologous chemotaxis is a mechanis cancer cells fall onto XXX</p>
<p>chemotaxis vs. mechanosensing</p>
<p>chemotaxis fails at high cell density</p>
<h3 id="motility-induced-phase-separation-of-deformable-cells">motility induced phase separation of deformable cells<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#motility-induced-phase-separation-of-deformable-cells"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>所谓 phase separation，就是一筐红绿豆自己分成两堆</p>
<p>rigid particles aggregate and sort without adhesion</p>
<p>2d layer of deformable active brownian particles</p>
<p>simulation: high deformability easier to phase separation, shorter collision time</p>
<p>BioPACIFIC program at UCSB and UCLA</p>
<h3 id="geometric-programming-of-collective-sensing-of-neural-cells">Geometric programming of collective sensing of neural cells<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#geometric-programming-of-collective-sensing-of-neural-cells"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Oregon State University, Chinese speaker</p>
<p>a cross shaped titch, with five wells at 4 tips and 1 crossing, (infinitely peridic? not sure)</p>
<p>flow switch of GM and ATP</p>
<p>longer period leads to more well synchronized nodes. edge probability pattern</p>
<h3 id="ear-hair-cells-tune-cochlea-to-criticality">Ear, hair cells tune cochlea to criticality<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#ear-hair-cells-tune-cochlea-to-criticality"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>impedance</p>
<p>seems have heard last year</p>
<p>Bo Sun Gourp member?</p>
<h2 id="social-interaction">Social Interaction<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#social-interaction"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>pretty big hall actually</p>
<h3 id="the-use-of-laser-speckle-spectroscopy-for-subtle-detection-of-infantile-ants">The Use of Laser Speckle Spectroscopy for Subtle Detection of Infantile Ants<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#the-use-of-laser-speckle-spectroscopy-for-subtle-detection-of-infantile-ants"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Geogeria tech</p>
<p>pixel photon intensity, not direct movies, to detect movements. also sounds like something last year.</p>
<h3 id="density-functional-fluctuation-theory-to-model-basketball">density functional fluctuation theory to model basketball<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#density-functional-fluctuation-theory-to-model-basketball"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>NBA has position data every 40 ms!</p>
<p>50 feet x 50 feet heatmap of shots</p>
<p>postulates: location of ball changes player spatial tendencies, 2 types of player defense and offense</p>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-8795A615-E1CB-44C4-B02B-3AB5884AA384.jpeg" alt="8795A615-E1CB-44C4-B02B-3AB5884AA384.jpeg"><figcaption>8795A615-E1CB-44C4-B02B-3AB5884AA384.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<p>forecast a play, evaluate a position, improving a player’s positioning.</p>
<h3 id="honeycomb-formation-under-geometric-frustrations">honeycomb formation under geometric frustrations<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#honeycomb-formation-under-geometric-frustrations"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>decentralized division of labour, to build honeycomb</p>
<p>a lot of energy cost, not always on flat plane.</p>
<p>3d printing to prepare substrate for bees, for data repeatability. basically they make plastic cells of different sizes, and see how bees build upon them.</p>
<p>geometric frustrations: shifts, tilts, sizes</p>
<p>forcing smaller cell size → X-ray microscopy</p>
<p>some ~24% of the cells are filled with wax</p>
<p>larger cells → tilting of wax walls, can be 3x bees’ normal honeycomb cell size</p>
<h3 id="winner-and-loser-emergence-in-zebrafish-fights">winner and loser emergence in zebrafish fights<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#winner-and-loser-emergence-in-zebrafish-fights"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>what is a fight, what is a winner and dominance, how fights start and end.</p>
<p>6 pairs fo fish, 3 body points of 2 fish in 3d, experimental tracking</p>
<p>defining winner: post-fight position asymmetry</p>
<p>fight-bout micostructure to <strong>mesoscopic</strong> fight-maneuvers.</p>
<p>phase space: <span class="katex"><span class="katex-mathml"><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><msub><mi>θ</mi><mi>W</mi></msub><mo separator="true">,</mo><msub><mi>θ</mi><mi>L</mi></msub><mo separator="true">,</mo><msub><mi>D</mi><mrow><mi>p</mi><mi>p</mi></mrow></msub><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">(\theta_W, \theta_L, D_{pp})</annotation></semantics></math></span><span class="katex-html" aria-hidden="true"><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:1.0361em;vertical-align:-0.2861em;"></span><span class="mopen">(</span><span class="mord"><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.02778em;">θ</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.3283em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0278em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight" style="margin-right:0.13889em;">W</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.15em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mpunct">,</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.1667em;"></span><span class="mord"><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.02778em;">θ</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.3283em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0278em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight">L</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.15em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mpunct">,</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.1667em;"></span><span class="mord"><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.02778em;">D</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.1514em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0278em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight">pp</span></span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.2861em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mclose">)</span></span></span></span></p>
<h3 id="chimera-states-among-synchronous-fireflies">Chimera states among synchronous fireflies<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#chimera-states-among-synchronous-fireflies"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Lewis and Cratsley Annu. Rev. Entomol. 2008. temporal patterns of different species</p>
<p><a href="https://fireflyexperience.org" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://fireflyexperience.org</a></p>
<p><span class="katex"><span class="katex-mathml"><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><msub><mover accent="true"><mi>θ</mi><mo>˙</mo></mover><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>ω</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><mfrac><mi>K</mi><mi>N</mi></mfrac><msub><mo>∑</mo><mi>j</mi></msub><mi>sin</mi><mo>⁡</mo><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><msub><mi>θ</mi><mi>j</mi></msub><mo>−</mo><msub><mi>θ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\dot\theta_i=\omega_i+\frac{K}{N}\sum_j\sin(\theta_j-\theta_i)</annotation></semantics></math></span><span class="katex-html" aria-hidden="true"><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:1.0813em;vertical-align:-0.15em;"></span><span class="mord"><span class="mord accent"><span class="vlist-t"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.9313em;"><span style="top:-3em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.02778em;">θ</span></span><span style="top:-3.2634em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="accent-body" style="left:-0.0556em;"><span class="mord">˙</span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.3117em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0278em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight">i</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.15em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2778em;"></span><span class="mrel">=</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2778em;"></span></span><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:0.7333em;vertical-align:-0.15em;"></span><span class="mord"><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.03588em;">ω</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.3117em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0359em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight">i</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.15em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2222em;"></span><span class="mbin">+</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2222em;"></span></span><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:1.3081em;vertical-align:-0.4358em;"></span><span class="mord"><span class="mopen nulldelimiter"></span><span class="mfrac"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.8723em;"><span style="top:-2.655em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight" style="margin-right:0.10903em;">N</span></span></span></span><span style="top:-3.23em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="frac-line" style="border-bottom-width:0.04em;"></span></span><span style="top:-3.394em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:3em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight" style="margin-right:0.07153em;">K</span></span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.345em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mclose nulldelimiter"></span></span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.1667em;"></span><span class="mop"><span class="mop op-symbol small-op" style="position:relative;top:0em;">∑</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.162em;"><span style="top:-2.4003em;margin-left:0em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight" style="margin-right:0.05724em;">j</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.4358em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.1667em;"></span><span class="mop">sin</span><span class="mopen">(</span><span class="mord"><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.02778em;">θ</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.3117em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0278em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight" style="margin-right:0.05724em;">j</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.2861em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2222em;"></span><span class="mbin">−</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.2222em;"></span></span><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:1em;vertical-align:-0.25em;"></span><span class="mord"><span class="mord mathnormal" style="margin-right:0.02778em;">θ</span><span class="msupsub"><span class="vlist-t vlist-t2"><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.3117em;"><span style="top:-2.55em;margin-left:-0.0278em;margin-right:0.05em;"><span class="pstrut" style="height:2.7em;"></span><span class="sizing reset-size6 size3 mtight"><span class="mord mathnormal mtight">i</span></span></span></span><span class="vlist-s">​</span></span><span class="vlist-r"><span class="vlist" style="height:0.15em;"><span></span></span></span></span></span></span><span class="mclose">)</span></span></span></span></p>
<p>chimera states for couples oscillators: part of the agents are synchronized, some are not, they coexist</p>
<p>example: unihemisphere sleep in marine mammals</p>
<p>South carolina, Congaree National Park</p>
<h3 id="synchronization-of-human-networks">Synchronization of human networks<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#synchronization-of-human-networks"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Moti Fridman (Bar Ilan University)</p>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-3790D8EF-864E-4107-9C44-2CD22D76AF8F.jpeg" alt="3790D8EF-864E-4107-9C44-2CD22D76AF8F.jpeg"><figcaption>3790D8EF-864E-4107-9C44-2CD22D76AF8F.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<p>previous works deal with the case where everyone sees everyone</p>
<p>violin players，但是成员互相看不到对方，one control position(? why need it)</p>
<p>bidirectional and delay</p>
<p>even number of plays give checker board out-of-phase pattern</p>
<p>odd number gives frustration, they need to ignore one of the plays, changing the connectivity of network, glass state</p>
<p>unidirectional network: humans change coupling strength at will when there is no delay</p>
<h2 id="mechanics-of-cells-and-tissues">Mechanics of cells and tissues<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mechanics-of-cells-and-tissues"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="division-and-differential-adhesion-drive-cell-self-segregation-during-embryo-morphogenesis">division and differential adhesion drive cell self-segregation during embryo morphogenesis<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#division-and-differential-adhesion-drive-cell-self-segregation-during-embryo-morphogenesis"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Voronoi cell model for cell monolayers</p>
<p>contact tension controls tissue structure</p>
<h3 id="mechanosensing-breast-cancer-spheroids">mechanosensing breast cancer spheroids<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mechanosensing-breast-cancer-spheroids"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>another Bo Sun group member.</p>
<p>to segment and track the cells in 3d: PEN projection enhanced network, on top of a Cellpose 2d neural network.</p>
<p>classify cell shape phenotypes with SVM</p>
<p>filopodia leads invasion</p>
<h3 id="kinetics-of-cell-aggregation">kinetics of cell aggregation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#kinetics-of-cell-aggregation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>cell-cell contacts: Guo et al Biophysics J. 2006</p>
<p>cell-substrate interactions:</p>
<p>感觉是个大杂烩，啥都有</p>
<p>matrix mediated mechanical interactions, so what does matrix mean?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>ChatGPT:</p>
<p>In biology, a matrix refers to a non-living or extracellular substance that provides structural support or serves as a medium for cellular interactions. The matrix can be made up of various components such as proteins, polysaccharides, and minerals, and it can be found in different biological contexts, such as bone, cartilage, connective tissue, and the extracellular matrix surrounding cells.</p>
<p>For example, in bone tissue, the extracellular matrix provides support and rigidity to the bone and is primarily composed of collagen fibers and mineralized calcium phosphate. In cartilage, the matrix is composed of collagen and proteoglycans and serves as a cushion between bones in joints. In connective tissue, the matrix provides support and allows for the exchange of nutrients and waste products between cells.</p>
<p>In summary, the matrix is an essential component of many biological tissues and provides structural support and a medium for cellular interactions.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="epithelia-tissues-as-hexnematic-liquid-cystals-and-instabilities">epithelia tissues as hexnematic liquid cystals, and instabilities<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#epithelia-tissues-as-hexnematic-liquid-cystals-and-instabilities"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Heager et al,  J. Exp Med 2020</p>
<p>hexatics in a channel, momentum conservation and orientation dynamics</p>
<p>dispersion relation and unstabilities</p>
<p>very classical dynamics study, as classical as those on textbooks</p>
<h3 id="multiscale-measurements-of-mechanical-stress-in-3d-co-cultures-using-a-deformable-micro-device">Multiscale measurements of mechanical stress in 3D co-cultures using a deformable micro-device<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#multiscale-measurements-of-mechanical-stress-in-3d-co-cultures-using-a-deformable-micro-device"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>巴斯德研究所</p>
<p>cell level reponse to tissue level mechanical xxx</p>
<p>mechanic stress on each cell depends on position and neighbors; global deformation is accumulation of local stressees.</p>
<h3 id="mechanoregulation-of-biofilm-homeostasis">Mechanoregulation of biofilm homeostasis<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mechanoregulation-of-biofilm-homeostasis"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland</p>
<p>biofilm in hydrogels</p>
<p>size control hypotheses: mechanical, growth rate, cell death</p>
<h3 id="mechanosensing-of-embedded-spheroids-and-cell-invasion">mechanosensing of embedded spheroids and cell invasion<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mechanosensing-of-embedded-spheroids-and-cell-invasion"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>inserted in a fibrous network consisting of collagen, and other proteins</p>
<p>3d <strong>vertex models</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ZhangTao-SJTU/tvm" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://github.com/ZhangTao-SJTU/tvm</a></p>
<h3 id="density-variation-of-fibroblasts-near-topological-defects">density variation of fibroblasts near topological defects<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#density-variation-of-fibroblasts-near-topological-defects"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>ridges to introduce topological defects, ridge height as proxy for ridge strength</p>
<p>shape dependent rate of division as the mechanism</p>
<p>cell density changes</p>
<h3 id="slicing-softly-with-paper">slicing softly with paper<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#slicing-softly-with-paper"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>paper cutting machine to use paper cutting into gels</p>
<p>small angle, thickness: buckling → cutting → indention</p>
<p>larger angle, only buckling → indention</p>
<p>appled stress must exceed critical threshold, but below buckling threshold</p>
<p>dangerous thickness: 65 microns</p>
<h3 id="vasculogenesis">Vasculogenesis<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#vasculogenesis"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>cardiovascular system is 1st organ system to form in a vertebrate embryo. 2 steps: vasculogenesis and angiogenesis</p>
<p>then totally lost</p>
<h3 id="cell-shape-and-fate-changes-in-3d-model-of-mammalian-hair-follicle-development">Cell shape and fate changes in 3D model of mammalian hair follicle development<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cell-shape-and-fate-changes-in-3d-model-of-mammalian-hair-follicle-development"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>3d vertex model</p>
<p>2 hypotheses: 1. changing cell autonomous properties; 2. extrinsic force. model 2 wins</p>
<p>WTH is E15.5 morphology</p>
<p>Lisa Manning group</p>
<h3 id="emergent-chirality-in-active-solid-rotation-of-pancreas-spheres">Emergent chirality in active solid rotation of pancreas spheres<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#emergent-chirality-in-active-solid-rotation-of-pancreas-spheres"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>ChatPDF and Humata.ai</strong></p>
<p>ChatPDF is almost unusable, there is no context, and cannot break lines. They even answered in French first</p>
<p>Humata.ai: The paper investigates the rotational dynamics of spherical tissues using murine pancreas-derived organoids as a model system. The study uses an active <strong>vertex model</strong> to demonstrate how the interplay between traction force and polarity alignment can account for distinct rotational dynamics. The study also investigates the emergence of chiral symmetry breaking in multicellular systems using experiments and simulations of rotating pancreas spheres. The authors propose that topological defects in the polarity field underlie the symmetry breaking. The article discusses the role of geometry in the behavior and properties of epithelial tissues, including cell division, patterning, and left-right symmetry breaking.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>语速还挺快</p>
<p>geometric constrains</p>
<p>3D上皮 collective dynamics, mouse pancres self organize into a sphere, inside filled with lumen</p>
<p>distinct rotational modes: rotation, rotation arrest, drift in rotation axis → mechanism?</p>
<p>active certex model: force balance, polarity dynamics</p>
<p>solid rotation, or fluid exchange of neighbors. solid body rotation fraction.</p>
<p>rotation axis drift is reminiscent of yielding like transition</p>
<p>cell shape orientation is almost stable, not a uniform random distribution when there is rotation, but uniform random without rotation</p>
<p>polarity dynamics: 2 types of solutions</p>
<p>other structures: cubodal, compact, multi-lumen: <strong>this is the proposed future direction</strong></p>
<h2 id="collective-behavior-1">collective behavior<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#collective-behavior-1"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="spying-on-bacteria-in-3d">spying on bacteria in 3d<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#spying-on-bacteria-in-3d"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Isolated cells:</p>
<p>Ball pit for E. coli cells for them to tumble</p>
<p>Active hopping and trapping</p>

<p>granular hydrogel matrix supports 3d printed colonies</p>
<p>Collective motion, not diffusion</p>
<p>Consumption and chemotaxis</p>
<p>How to keep front together: Change initial position. Chemostatic velocity</p>
<p>Sensing = F(c)</p>
<h3 id="multicelluarity-w-differentiable-molecular-dynamics-simulations">multicelluarity w/ Differentiable Molecular Dynamics Simulations<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#multicelluarity-w-differentiable-molecular-dynamics-simulations"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Jax-MD: <a href="http://github.com/google/jax-md" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">github.com/google/jax-md</a></p>
<p>machanism for regulating division</p>
<p>“learned params consistently yield homogeneous growth”</p>
<p>don’t like this project very much. which part is done by the speaker?</p>
<h3 id="collective-behavior-of-swimmers-in-intermediate-reynold-number">collective behavior of swimmers in intermediate Reynold number<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#collective-behavior-of-swimmers-in-intermediate-reynold-number"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>model of dumbbell in fluid, 2D [torque and force] free</p>
<p>pair of dumbbells: puller and pusher</p>
<h3 id="chemotactic-motility-induced-phase-separation">Chemotactic motility-induced phase separation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#chemotactic-motility-induced-phase-separation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p><strong>Chemotactic</strong></p>
<p>student of the invited speaker of this session, award winner.</p>
<p>motility-induced phase separation: 抖豆子抖成堆</p>
<p>chemotaxis: directed motion in response to chemical gradient</p>
<p>particle volume fraction, chemoattractant concentration,</p>
<p>sets up an allowed region of phase separation</p>
<p>arxiv:2301.12345</p>
<h3 id="anomalous-collective-dynamics-of-dividing-chemotactic-agents">Anomalous collective dynamics of dividing chemotactic agents<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#anomalous-collective-dynamics-of-dividing-chemotactic-agents"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Chemotaxis + population dynamics</p>
<p>non-equilibrium continuous phase transition</p>
<p>some kind of reaction diffusion equations for <span class="katex"><span class="katex-mathml"><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>ρ</mi><mo separator="true">,</mo><mi>c</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\rho, c</annotation></semantics></math></span><span class="katex-html" aria-hidden="true"><span class="base"><span class="strut" style="height:0.625em;vertical-align:-0.1944em;"></span><span class="mord mathnormal">ρ</span><span class="mpunct">,</span><span class="mspace" style="margin-right:0.1667em;"></span><span class="mord mathnormal">c</span></span></span></span></p>
<p><strong>chemotactic</strong> interactions can alter {} near critical point</p>
<h3 id="crowds-with-large-pressures">Crowds with large pressures<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#crowds-with-large-pressures"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>non-equilibrium</p>
<p>microscopic: Vicsek model, Helbing-Molnar model; macroscopic: mechanical spectroscopy of insect swarms, equation of state</p>
<p>sys behave like equilibrium: Silverberg 2013 PRL</p>
<p>why works? difference of time scales: relaxation time >> collision time.</p>
<p>agents packed: potential energt not equi-partition, but kinetic energy are.</p>
<h3 id="phenotype-probability-distinguishes-mutants-from-wildtype-social-bacteria">phenotype probability distinguishes mutants from wildtype social bacteria<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#phenotype-probability-distinguishes-mutants-from-wildtype-social-bacteria"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>M. xanthus form persistent or not persistent dunes.</p>
<h2 id="morphogenesis">Morphogenesis<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#morphogenesis"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="tension-triangle">tension triangle<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#tension-triangle"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>8:30-8:40</p>
<p>Order and anisotropic form coherent T1 that drive flow</p>
<p>A lot of UCSB, actually one group having 2 talks back to back</p>
<p>Tension isogonal decomposition</p>
<p>Could be applied to wing disk, neurolation,</p>
<h3 id="from-gene-to-geometry">from gene to geometry<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#from-gene-to-geometry"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Cells → sheet → tube → cortex</p>
<p>multi view confocal, Bayesian based deconvolution, deep tissue imaging</p>
<p>Knockout and shape differs</p>
<p>TubLUAR: tube like surface Lagrangian analysis resource</p>
<p>How gene → calcium signaling → muscle contraction → endodem strains → organ shape</p>
<h2 id="plant-biology">plant Biology<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#plant-biology"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="root-hair">root hair<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#root-hair"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>self anchoring, 仿生根 robot, can dig into fake moon soil, for soil sampling and sensor implanting</p>
<h3 id="heterogeneous-cellular-growth-in-root">Heterogeneous cellular growth in root<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#heterogeneous-cellular-growth-in-root"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Directly connected to organismal shape</p>
<p>cell behavior to organisms</p>
<p>Discrete element simulation</p>
<p>Meristematic and elongation zone</p>
<h3 id="turing-pattern-in-vegetation">Turing pattern in vegetation<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#turing-pattern-in-vegetation"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Experiment: Australien fairy circles regenerated</p>
<p>WebGL and JavaScript</p>
<h3 id="network-architecture-of-plant-pathogen-interactions">network architecture of plant pathogen interactions<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#network-architecture-of-plant-pathogen-interactions"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-D185C1B7-F5EB-4629-B767-0ECF7F72C591.jpeg" alt="D185C1B7-F5EB-4629-B767-0ECF7F72C591.jpeg"><figcaption>D185C1B7-F5EB-4629-B767-0ECF7F72C591.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="rehype-figure"><img src="/blog/photos/2023-03-12-03A05C17-8E19-4B30-B449-1A99D02093A9.jpeg" alt="03A05C17-8E19-4B30-B449-1A99D02093A9.jpeg"><figcaption>03A05C17-8E19-4B30-B449-1A99D02093A9.jpeg</figcaption></figure>
<p>Translation/degradation, xxx, xxx</p>
<p>Simple model. complex systems</p>
<p>Rockefeller U.</p>
<h3 id="water-solubility-of-hydrophobic-xxx-with-phytoglycogenpg-nano-particles">water solubility of hydrophobic xxx with phytoglycogen(PG) nano particles<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#water-solubility-of-hydrophobic-xxx-with-phytoglycogenpg-nano-particles"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>University of Guelph, in Canada</p>
<p>Astaxanthin-</p>
<p>Carotenoid solubilization strategy</p>
<p>OSA modification changes absorption spectra</p>
<h2 id="emergent-behavior-in-biological-systems">Emergent behavior in biological systems<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#emergent-behavior-in-biological-systems"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<h3 id="emergent-spatiotemporal-communication-patterns-in-insect-swarms">Emergent Spatiotemporal Communication Patterns in Insect Swarms<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#emergent-spatiotemporal-communication-patterns-in-insect-swarms"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Chemical signaling (bees) and visual signaling (fireflies)</p>
<p>Worker bees scent to amplify the feromon of the queen to locate the queen</p>
<p>Also Happens in fed bees to locate food</p>

<p>Visual signals by fireflies</p>
<p>非线性动力学的课本居然有 synchronization, slide 和之前看过的一样</p>
<p>Can only see a small portions of fireflies in the wild</p>
<p>Controlled environment</p>
<p>Talking to fireflies with LED</p>
<h3 id="anatomy-of-e-coli-colony-expansion">anatomy of E. coli colony expansion<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#anatomy-of-e-coli-colony-expansion"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Height depends on glucose concentration</p>
<h3 id="mechanical-information-processing-by-action-cytoskeleton">mechanical information processing by action cytoskeleton<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#mechanical-information-processing-by-action-cytoskeleton"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Focal adhesion</p>
<p>Pretty biology heavy</p>
<h3 id="cryoet">CryoET<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#cryoet"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>Tomography</p>
<p>Capture topological features on sparse density data</p>
<p>Image voxels and compare with alpha fold candidates.</p>
<p>Is this risky for cyclic reasoning?</p>
<h3 id="protein-assembly">protein assembly<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#protein-assembly"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h3>
<p>最后一天，没有心气记笔记了……</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[.py | Python's Interpreter, Editor, and Virtual Environment]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/python-interpreter-editor-virtualenv</link>
            <guid>https://blog.mountaye.com/en/articles/python-interpreter-editor-virtualenv</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Really, what are Python's interpreter, editor, and virtual environment]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the previous post "<a href="python-installation-and-configuration">Configuring Python Development Environment on Windows 10</a>", I did roughly three things:</p>
<ul>
<li>First, I installed the Python interpreter.</li>
<li>Second, I installed VSCode on the computer.</li>
<li>Third, as we know, is the virtual environment, virtualenv.</li>
</ul>
<p>If there's something else worth mentioning, it's to add a bit of "what" alongside the "how". To make the article flow better, I plan to rearrange the order: first, talk about the editor, then the interpreter, and finally, the virtual environment. Although the article is based on Python, these concepts apply to almost all general-purpose programming languages. Because I'm not from a computer science background, this article is just my study notes, so if there are any inaccuracies, feel free to point them out.</p>
<h2 id="editor">Editor<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#editor"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>First, let's do an experiment. Rename the Python file <code>hello.py</code> created in the previous tutorial, change the extension <code>.py</code> to <code>.txt</code>, then double-click to open the file. What happens? In the Windows system, the most ordinary Notepad window pops up, displaying Python statements in black text on a white background, unlike in VSCode where different statements have different colors, but the content is exactly the same.</p>
<p>Furthermore, you can directly execute the content of a <code>.txt</code> file in the command line with the Python interpreter (<code>py -m hello.txt</code>), with the same effect as <code>.py</code>.</p>
<p>The <code>.py</code> extension doesn't do anything special; like a <code>.txt</code> file, its content is simply a string of characters readable by humans. Such files are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_file" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">text files</a>. An editor is a program that handles text files. Notepad is one type of editor, as is VSCode.</p>
<p>Since Notepad can already write Python code, why bother installing VSCode? Indeed, some people really only use Notepad or other built-in editors of the operating system to write Python code (there's even a video on YouTube of someone writing code in Microsoft Word); then debug the program using the command line. However, VSCode is specifically developed for programmers, providing many features that default editors lack, such as syntax highlighting, which highlights functions, variables, and keywords in different colors.</p>
<h2 id="compiler--interpreter">Compiler / Interpreter<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#compiler--interpreter"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>In addition to text files, the second type of file mentioned in this article is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_file" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">binary file</a>.</p>
<p>Computers cannot directly understand characters recognized by humans. At the lowest level, classic computers understand only 0s and 1s represented in different ways. Although all files are ultimately binary at the lowest level, the term "binary file" is generally used specifically to refer to files other than text files. Since image files, video files, etc., have their own names, the files referred to by this term are basically related to software programs, files that can be executed by computers.</p>
<p>Humans recognize characters, computers recognize only 0s and 1s, so the most intuitive approach is to translate text files into binary files. This translation process is called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compiler" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">compilation</a>, and the software that can accomplish this is called a compiler. Once compilation is complete, the compiler exits, and to execute the program, the computer simply executes the compiled executable file.</p>
<p>However, compilation has a problem: the entire software needs to be compiled into a complete executable with all source code text files written. As the scale of the software grows, the resources and time required for compilation increase; once a modification is made, the entire project needs to be recompiled. Many times, we only want to quickly know the effect of a command in a large project; compilation is not suitable for such scenarios.</p>
<p>Thus, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interpreter_(computing)" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">interpreter</a> emerged. This type of program is much more complex than a compiler. It runs whenever we execute a command in a programming language, allowing us to enter commands one by one, remembering the context of the code, and even remembering the results of our previous commands. The cost is that even for large projects, it needs to analyze and interpret line by line, and its computational resource overhead and speed are not as efficient as compilation.</p>
<p>Python is a (official implementation) programming language that uses an interpreter. The <code>python-***.exe</code> file we download from the official website is the Python interpreter. This also means that Python programs tend to perform less well than programs written by C/C++ programmers of the same level. However, due to its suitability for trial and error with single-line execution, Python is quite popular in research fields.</p>
<p>Of course, Python's characteristics are far more than just being an interpreted language. It is also:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://program-think.blogspot.com/2009/08/why-choose-python-1-script.html" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Scripting language</a></li>
<li><a href="https://program-think.blogspot.com/2009/08/why-choose-python-2-dynamic.html" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dynamic language</a></li>
<li><a href="https://program-think.blogspot.com/2010/08/why-choose-python-3-oop.html" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Object-oriented language</a></li>
<li><a href="https://program-think.blogspot.com/2010/08/why-choose-python-3-oop.html" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Functional programming language</a></li>
<li><a href="https://program-think.blogspot.com/2010/08/why-choose-python-5-tools.html" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">...</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="virtual-environment">Virtual Environment<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#virtual-environment"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>Once I asked my girlfriend what IDE she uses to write Python, and she proudly replied that her MacBook comes with Python, so she can run it directly from the command line... The problem wasn't that she didn't answer my question directly (actually, thinking about it, she did answer part of the question), but rather that running the system's built-in Python interpreter or other programming language interpreters or compilers directly from the command line is a dangerous practice common among beginner programmers.</p>
<p>Fortunately, Windows is fine; after all, it's an operating system aimed at the general consumer, so it doesn't come with Python pre-installed. However, for more geek-oriented operating systems like Linux and the BSD family, things are different. These operating systems (or their distributions) often come pre-installed with Python. This Python isn't intended for users to develop their own programs but rather for the many system tools written in Python to call upon. Since the version of Python is usually controlled by the package manager of the distribution, it often lags behind the latest Python version for some time to avoid bugs in the new version and to give developers of system tools time to update their code. So, if you use this version of Python for development and accidentally upgrade Python, it's likely to cause some system functionality to malfunction.</p>
<p>A virtual environment is Python's solution to this problem. We can install a version of Python different from the system's default version but not add this interpreter to the system path, so the operating system is unaware of the existence of this version of Python. When creating a virtual environment, we specify the use of this specific version of Python. So, after activating the virtual environment, it becomes the Python we need for development, and exiting the virtual environment returns to the Python used by system tools.</p>
<p>Moreover, even if two projects use the same version of Python and both use the system's default version, virtual environments still have a place. Most programs require dependency onlibrary code written by others, called libraries. Different projects may depend on different library code, or different versions of the same library. In this case, you can create separate virtual environments and install the libraries corresponding to each project. Projects can be isolated from each other.</p>
<h2 id="editor--interpreter--compiler--virtual-environment-management----ide">Editor + Interpreter / Compiler + Virtual Environment Management + ... = IDE<a aria-hidden="true" tabindex="-1" href="#editor--interpreter--compiler--virtual-environment-management----ide"><span class="icon icon-link"></span></a></h2>
<p>It's too cumbersome to install so many different programs for Python development. Can't it be done with just one click? Of course it can. A program that integrates various tools used in the development process is called an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">integrated development environment (IDE)</a>. For Python, the most famous IDE is undoubtedly <a href="https://www.anaconda.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Anaconda</a>.</p>
<p>Then why don't I use it? Of course, I've used it before, but after hearing about the fame of VSCode and trying it out, I don't want to go back. Writing Python requires editing <code>.py</code> files, writing blog posts requires editing <code>.md</code> files, and some blog features require JavaScript. Essentially, all these tasks involve editing text files. In an editor like VSCode, everything is done together. So, programs like Spyder and Jupyter Lab in Anaconda seem redundant.</p>
<p>"Doing one thing well" is also part of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Unix philosophy</a>. But the problem is that different people have different definitions of "one thing". Some people think making breakfast is one thing, while others think it involves several things like heating milk, frying eggs, and toasting bread. Who is right?</p>
<p>Perhaps both are right, but Editor + Interpreter + ... is upstream on the chain of contempt compared to IDE. You may disagree with this, but you should know it; otherwise, when others show off, you might feel embarrassed for not being prepared.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>